<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD v1.1 20151215//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.3 20070202//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName journalpublishing.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.3?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName jp2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Medicine (Baltimore)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Medicine (Baltimore)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">MEDI</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Medicine</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0025-7974</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1536-5964</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Wolters Kluwer Health</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6200462</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">30290658</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">MD-D-18-00954</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000012686</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="art-access-id">12686</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="hwp-journal-coll"><subject>5750</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research Article</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Observational Study</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Young male breast cancer, a small crowd, the survival, and prognosis?</article-title><subtitle>A population-based study</subtitle></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Naikun</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>a</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Xiaohui</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>b</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Hongju</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3"><sup>c</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Haiyong</given-names></name><degrees>MD, PhD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff4"><sup>d</sup></xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp"><sup>&#x02217;</sup></xref></contrib></contrib-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="editor"><name><surname>Kok.</surname><given-names>Victor C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1"><label>a</label>Department of Oncology, Central Hospital of Yidu affiliated to Weifang Medical College, Weifang</aff><aff id="aff2"><label>b</label>Research Service Office, Shandong Liaocheng People's Hospital</aff><aff id="aff3"><label>c</label>Department of Oncology, Liaocheng Infectious Disease Hospital, Liaocheng</aff><aff id="aff4"><label>d</label>Department of internal Medicine-Oncology, Shandong Cancer Hospital and Institute, Shandong Cancer Hospital affiliated to Shandong University, Shandong Academy of Medical Sciences, Jinan, China.</aff><author-notes id="cor1"><corresp><label>&#x02217;</label>Correspondence: Haiyong Wang, Department of Internal Medicine-Oncology, Shandong Cancer Hospital and Institute, Shandong Cancer Hospital affiliated to Shandong University, Shandong Academy of Medical Sciences, Jinan 250117, China (e-mail: <email>wanghaiyong6688@126.com</email>).</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>10</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>05</day><month>10</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><volume>97</volume><issue>40</issue><elocation-id>e12686</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>3</day><month>2</month><year>2018</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>8</day><month>9</month><year>2018</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2018 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2018</copyright-year><license license-type="open-access" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0"><license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution-Non Commercial License 4.0 (CCBY-NC), where it is permissible to download, share, remix, transform, and buildup the work provided it is properly cited. The work cannot be used commercially without permission from the journal. <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0</ext-link></license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="medi-97-e12686.pdf"/><abstract abstract-type="toc"><p>Supplemental Digital Content is available in the text</p></abstract><abstract><title>Abstract</title><p>Women diagnosed with breast cancer at young age often have poorprognoses. Yet, few studies have focused on the prognoses of young men with breast cancer. We therefore used Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results (SEER) population-based data and identified 151 male patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years between 1988 and 2012. Propensity score matching analysis was used to balance the clinical variables among different groups. Kaplan&#x02013;Meier curves were applied to compare the survival differences. The subgroup variables on cancer-specific survival (CSS) and overall survival (OS) were analyzed by the Cox proportional hazard model. Results showed that male patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 had a significant OS benefit compared with those aged &#x02265;40 years (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.001). The significant difference of the CSS was not found (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003e;&#x0200a;.05). Compared with the male patients with breast cancer aged &#x02265;40, those aged &#x0003c;40 had significant OS benefit in most subgroups (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.05). Compared with the female patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40, the male patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 had worse OS and CSS benefit only in the subgroup with progesterone receptor and estrogen receptor positive (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.05). In conclusion, we demonstrated that young male patients with breast cancer had better OS compared with elder male patients with breast cancer. However, the survival benefit was not found compared with young female patients with breast cancer.</p></abstract><kwd-group><title>Keywords</title><kwd>male breast cancer</kwd><kwd>prognosis</kwd><kwd>Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results</kwd><kwd>survival</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>OPEN-ACCESS</meta-name><meta-value>TRUE</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec><label>1</label><title>Introduction</title><p>Male breast cancer is an uncommon disease. It accounts for only about 1% of all breast carcinomas all over the world and distinguishes from female breast cancer in some aspects of tumor characteristics.<sup>[<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]</sup> Importantly, the incidence of male breast cancer has been gradually on the rise during the past decades.<sup>[<xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]</sup> For a long time, our understanding of male breast cancer, such as genetic characteristics, hormonal conditions, are not as profound as that of female breast cancer. Interestingly, due to its low incidence, studies reporting the clinical characteristics and optimal treatment of male breast cancer are usually referred to those on female breast cancer.<sup>[<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]</sup> In fact, the prognostic factors and treatment strategies in male breast cancer extrapolated from some related studies of female breast cancer are controversial.<sup>[<xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]</sup> Therefore, it is imperative to comprehensively understand the molecular mechanism and prognostic factors of male breast cancer.</p><p>As known to us all, breast cancer has been more prevalent among young women.<sup>[<xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</sup> Women diagnosed with breast cancer at young age often have poor prognoses.<sup>[<xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]</sup> Studies have shown that young women with breast cancer are more likely to be presented with luminal B subtype and at advanced stages, to be of higher grade and with more lymphovascular invasion. Besides, women diagnosed with breast cancer at younger age are more likely to be poorly differentiated, human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 (HER-2)-positive and estrogen receptor (ER)-negative, which contributes to the worsened prognoses.<sup>[<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]</sup> Because of the specificity of young male patients with breast cancer, we attempt to investigate if their prognoses differ from those of the young female patients with breast cancer and the old male patients with breast cancer. Relevant researches focusing on the particular population are rare due to its rather smaller proportion. However, it is worth to further study the prognostic factors affecting the survival of young male patients with breast cancer.</p><p>In this study, we evaluated the clinicopathologic features and prognosis in men diagnosed with breast cancer prior to 40 years old. The population-based data were extracted from the Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results (SEER) registry in the United States published annually by the Data Analysis and Interpretation Branch of the National Cancer Institute, MD.<sup>[<xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]</sup></p></sec><sec><label>2</label><title>Methods</title><sec><label>2.1</label><title>Patient selection</title><p>The SEER database was used to identify all young male patients with breast cancer diagnosed between 1988 and 2012.<sup>[<xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]</sup> A total of 18 population-based cancer registries in the United States were included in the current SEER database. The SEER&#x02217;Stat software (SEER&#x02217;Stat 8.2.1) was used to identify patients. All cases before 1988 were excluded because of incomplete information on staging and surgery. The inclusion criteria were malignant behavior and the diagnosis was confirmed microscopically, with known age, active follow-up, and the age at diagnosis with &#x0003c;40 years. The exclusion criteria were benign or borderline tumors, with unknown age, unknown cause of death, unknown survival months.</p></sec><sec><label>2.2</label><title>Ethics statement</title><p>As previously described,<sup>[<xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]</sup> this study was mainly based on the SEER database and was conducted in compliance with the Helsinki Declaration. We obtained permission to access the SEER program research data files and the reference number is 11824-Nov2014. The informed consent was not required since personal identifying information was not involved. This study was approved by the ethics committee of the Shandong Cancer Hospital affiliated to Shandong University.</p></sec><sec><label>2.3</label><title>Statistical analysis</title><p>For all patients, the following variables were analyzed: Race, American Joint Committee on Cancer (AJCC) stage, Grade, Metastasis status, ER status, progesterone receptor (PR) status, Radiation. In addition, the overall survival (OS) and cancer-specific survival (CSS) were regarded as the primary endpoint of this study and extracted from the SEER database. Chi-squared tests were used to compare the patient's baseline characteristics. The Kaplan&#x02013;Meier estimates were used to generate the survival curves and the Log Rank test was applied to analyze the differences among the curves. The propensity score matching analysis was used to determine the comparative patients. In detail, the propensity score matching was preformed according to 1:1 matching and the matching tolerance is 0. Between the male patients &#x0003c;40 and the male patients &#x02265;40, a total of 89 patients were matched successfully. Between the male patients &#x0003c;40 and the female patients &#x0003c;40, a total of 86 patients were matched successfully. The Cox proportional hazard analysis was used to analyze the survival based on different subgroup variables, and the concrete results were presented in the forest plot. All statistical tests were 2-sided, and a <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.05 was considered statistically significant. The statistical software SPSS 22.0 (SPSS, Chicago, IL) was used for all data analyses.</p></sec></sec><sec><label>3</label><title>Results</title><sec><label>3.1</label><title>Patient demographics</title><p>There were 151 cases of male patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years reported in the SEER database from 1988 to 2012. Importantly, for a better comparison, we also identified 6930 cases of male patients with breast cancer aged &#x02265;40 years and 52,710 cases of female patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years in the SEER database from 1988 to 2012. The clinical characteristics and pathologic features of all the patients are summarized in Table <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">1</xref>. There was a statistically significant difference in the composition of Race, AJCC stage, Grade, Metastasis status, ER status, PR status, and Radiation (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.001). In addition, compared with male patients with breast cancer aged &#x02265;40 years, the young male patients with breast cancer were more likely to be black race (18.54% vs 12.64%), less tumor at grade I/II (42.38% vs 55.18%), lower hormone receptor positive (67.5% vs 76.68% for ER status and 54.30% vs 67.29% for PR status). Compared with female patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years, the young male patients with breast cancer were more likely to be hormone receptor positive (67.5% vs 52.22 for ER status and 54.30% vs 46.14% for PR status). Interestingly, fewer young male patients with breast cancer received radiation therapy (27.81% vs 45.01%). The detailed statistical results are summarized in Table <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">1</xref>.</p><table-wrap id="T1" position="float"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Characteristics of patients from SEER database from 1988 to 2012.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e12686-g001"/></table-wrap></sec><sec><label>3.2</label><title>Prognostic analysis of young male patients with breast cancer</title><p>The prognoses of male breast cancer and female breast cancer were further analyzed using Kaplan&#x02013;Meier estimates. As shown in Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">1</xref>, the OS of young male patients with breast cancer was significantly higher than male patients with breast cancer aged &#x02265;40 years (&#x003c7;<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;33.929, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.001) (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">1</xref>A). However, there was no significant OS difference between young male patients with breast cancer and young female patients with breast cancer (&#x003c7;<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0.006, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.939) (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">1</xref>A). Interestingly, the significant differences of the CSS among the 3 groups were not found (&#x003c7;<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;1.024, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.599) (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">1</xref>B).</p><fig id="F1" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>The over survival (OS) and cancer-specific survival (CSS) curves in male breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years, male breast cancer aged &#x02265;40 years, female breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years between 1988 and 2012. (A) The OS curves: male breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years vs male breast cancer aged &#x02265;40 years (&#x003c7;<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;33.929, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.001); male breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years vs female breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years (&#x003c7;<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0.006, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.939). (B) The CSS curves of 3 different groups (&#x003c7;<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;1.024, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.599).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e12686-g002"/></fig></sec><sec><label>3.3</label><title>Propensity score matching analysis</title><p>The clinical baseline was significantly different among the patients, which may lead to different prognosis. To eliminate the influence of clinical baseline and the sample size on survival, propensity score matching was conducted to reevaluate the prognosis. After performing the propensity score matching analysis according to 1:1 matching, all variable factors were well balanced between the 3 groups (all, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003e;&#x0200a;.05) (Supplemental Table 2, Supplemental Table 3). Then the prognoses of male breast cancer and female breast cancer were further analyzed using Kaplan&#x02013;Meier estimates. The results showed that the OS of young male patients with breast cancer was still significantly longer than male patients with breast cancer aged &#x02265;40 years (&#x003c7;<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;14.64, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.001) (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">2</xref>A). However, the significant difference between young male patients with breast cancer and male patients with breast cancer aged &#x02265;40 was not found in CSS (&#x003c7;<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0.354, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.552) (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">2</xref>B). Interestingly, there was no significant difference between young male patients with breast cancer and young female patients with breast cancer in CSS and OS (&#x003c7;<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;3.085, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.079 for OS; &#x003c7;<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;2.589, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.018 for CSS) (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">2</xref>C and D).</p><fig id="F2" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>The over survival (OS) and cancer-specific survival (CSS) curves in male breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years, male breast cancer aged &#x02265;40 years, female breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years between 1988 and 2012 after doing propensity score matching analysis. (A) The OS curves: male breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years vs male breast cancer aged &#x02265;40 years (&#x003c7;<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;14.64, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.001). (B) The CSS curves: male breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years vs male breast cancer aged &#x02265;40 years (&#x003c7;<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0.354, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.552). (C) The OS curves: male breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years vs female breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years (&#x003c7;<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;3.085, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.079). (D) The CSS curves: male breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years vs female breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years (&#x003c7;<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;2.589, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.018).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e12686-g003"/></fig></sec><sec><label>3.4</label><title>Subgroup analysis between male patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 and &#x02265;40</title><p>The univariate and multivariate Cox proportional hazard analysis was used to analyze the survival prognosis factors. Then the forest plot was applied to depict the subgroup analysis to adjust for other variables including grade, stage, metastasis, radiotherapy, and PR/ER. The result showed that the patients aged &#x0003c;40 had no significant CSS benefit compared with the patients aged &#x02265;40 among all the subgroup variables (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">3</xref>). However, the result showed that the patients aged &#x0003c;40 had significant OS benefit compared with the patients aged &#x02265;40 among most of the subgroup variables (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F4">4</xref>). The subgroup variables including white race (hazard ratio [HR]: 3.156; 95% confidence interval [CI]: 1.881&#x02013;5.295; <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.001); grades I and II (HR: 2.665; 95% CI: 1.367&#x02013;5.196; <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.004); grade III (HR: 2.173; 95% CI: 1.181&#x02013;3.996; <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.013); stages I and II (HR: 4.516; 95% CI: 2.555&#x02013;7.982; <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.001); no metastasis (HR: 3.065; 95% CI: 1.887&#x02013;4.980; <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.001); no radiotherapy (HR: 2.649; 95% CI: 1.548&#x02013;4.533; <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.001); PR positive (HR: 2.025; 95% CI: 1.270&#x02013;3.230; <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.003); PR negative (HR: 2.235; 95% CI: 1.378&#x02013;3.907; <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.002); ER positive (HR: 2.158; 95% CI: 1.256&#x02013;3.708; <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.001); ER negative (HR: 2.932; 95% CI: 1.309&#x02013;6.568; <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.001).</p><fig id="F3" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>The forest plot for hazard ratio to compare cancer-specific survival (CSS) between male breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years and male breast cancer aged &#x02265;40 years according to different variables. CI = confidence interval, ER = estrogen receptor, HR = hazard ratio, PR = progesterone receptor.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e12686-g004"/></fig><fig id="F4" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>The forest plot for hazard ratio to compare over survival between male breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years and male breast cancer aged &#x02265;40 years according to different variables. CI = confidence interval, ER = estrogen receptor, HR = hazard ratio, OS = over survival, PR = progesterone receptor.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e12686-g005"/></fig></sec><sec><label>3.5</label><title>Subgroup analysis between young male patients with breast cancer and young female patients with breast cancer</title><p>Analogously, the univariate and multivariate Cox proportional hazard analysis was used to analyze the survival prognostic factors. Then forest plot was applied to depict the subgroup analysis to adjust for other variables including grade, stage, metastasis, radiotherapy, and PR/ER. Results showed that the male patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 had no significant survival benefit including CSS and OS compared with the female patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 among most of the subgroup variables (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F5">5</xref>). Only in the PR and ER positive subgroup, the male patients with breast cancer had worse CSS benefit compared to the female patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 (HR: 0.470; 95% CI: 0.223&#x02013;0.990; <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.047 for PR; HR: 0.287; 95% CI: 0.114&#x02013;0.728; <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.009 for ER) (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F5">5</xref>). Importantly, compared with the female patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40, the male patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 also had worse OS benefit in PR and ER positive subgroup (HR: 0.482; 95% CI: 0.254&#x02013;0.914; <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.025 for PR; HR: 0.375; 95% CI: 0.170&#x02013;0.827; <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.015 for ER) (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F6">6</xref>).</p><fig id="F5" position="float"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>The forest plot for hazard ratio to compare cancer-specific survival (CSS) between male breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years and female breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years according to different variables. CI = confidence interval, ER = estrogen receptor, HR = hazard ratio, PR = progesterone receptor.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e12686-g006"/></fig><fig id="F6" position="float"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>The forest plot for hazard ratio to compare over survival (OS) between male breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years and female breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 years according to different variables. CI = confidence interval, ER = estrogen receptor, HR = hazard ratio, PR = progesterone receptor.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e12686-g007"/></fig></sec></sec><sec><label>4</label><title>Discussion</title><p>Male breast cancer is a rare disease, accounting for about 1% of all breast malignancies.<sup>[<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]</sup> Most male patients with breast cancer are diagnosed between the age of 60 and 70 years old.<sup>[<xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]</sup> However, there are few literatures reporting the clinicopathologic features and prognostic factors of young male breast cancer. Interestingly, studies have reported that the tumor biologic behavior of younger women diagnosed with breast cancer tend to be more aggressive, which would consequently lead to a worsened prognosis compared with older women.<sup>[<xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]</sup> Therefore, an in depth understanding of young male breast cancer is urgently needed.</p><p>Most studies have recommended that breast cancer should be screened as early as 40 years old for average-risk women.<sup>[<xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]</sup> In our study, male patients with breast cancer younger than 39 years old were classified into the category of young male breast cancer. Some studies have shown that the incidence of breast cancer is on the rise for young women.<sup>[<xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</sup> Similarly, our results indicated that the incidence of young male breast cancer also demonstrated a trend of gradual increase, which is consistent with previous studies.<sup>[<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup> In addition, the prognoses of male breast cancer were demonstrated to be worse than those of their female counterparts.<sup>[<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup> However, in our study, we found that there was no obvious difference in OS or CSS between young men and young women with breast cancer. Interestingly, some studies also showed that the prognoses were similar if patients&#x02019; age, cancer stage, and other prognostic factors are controlled between male patients with breast cancer and female patients with breast cancer.<sup>[<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,<xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</sup> Importantly, we found that the OS of young male patients was significantly longer than those of elder male patients with breast cancer. Interestingly, there was no obvious difference in CSS between young men and old men with breast cancer. In this regard, our study differs from some studies documenting that young female patients with breast cancer are often associated with unfavorable prognosis compared with their elder counterpart.<sup>[<xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]</sup> In addition, the average age of male patients diagnosed with breast cancer was higher than that of female patients with breast cancer, which could possibly increase the risk of suffering from other diseases.<sup>[<xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]</sup> Undeniably, the rather relatively smaller sample size in young patients in our study may be also an influencing factor.</p><p>Importantly, due to the clinical baseline imbalances intrinsic in a retrospective study, the propensity score matching analysis according to 1:1 matching was applied to regenerate clinical baseline data. Our results also showed male patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 had a significantly OS benefit only compared with the male patients with breast cancer aged &#x02265;40. The significant difference of the CSS among the 3 groups was not found. Up till now, no related studies have focused on young male patients with breast cancer. Interestingly, compared with the male patients with breast cancer aged &#x02265;40 years, our subgroup analysis showed that male patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40 had no significantly CSS benefit in all variables; however, the significant OS benefit could be found in most variables including white race, grades I and II/III, stages I and II, no metastasis, no radiotherapy, PR positive/negative, and ER positive/negative. In fact, some studies have shown that race is a prognostic factor for male patients with breast cancer.<sup>[<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,<xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]</sup> Interestingly, in our study, we found that young white race patients had a better OS in male patients with breast cancer. Tumor stage was a prognostic factor for OS by univariate analysis. However, it was not an independent factor by multivariate analysis.<sup>[<xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]</sup> In our study, we found that for patients at tumor stages I and II, the young male patients with breast cancer had a better prognosis. For the ER/PR status, studies indicated that the expressions of ER and PR were higher in male patients with breast cancer as compared with those in female patients with breast cancer.<sup>[<xref rid="R26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>,<xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>]</sup> However, due to the distinct functions in male breast cancer compared to the female breast cancer, some studies demonstrated that the hormone receptor status has no effect on survival in male breast cancer.<sup>[<xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>,<xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]</sup> In our study, regardless of the ER/PR state, the young male patients with breast cancer had a better prognosis compared to the patients aged &#x02265;40. However, compared to the female patients with breast cancer aged &#x0003c;40, the subgroup young male patients with breast cancer with ER/PR positive had a worse OS and CSS. Our results demonstrated that young male patients with breast cancer did not benefit from endocrine therapy. Interestingly, some studies showed that patients with male breast cancer received fewer chemotherapy, whereas no statistical difference was observed in the use of hormone treatment.<sup>[<xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]</sup></p><p>Undeniably, this study has several limitations. First, due to the absence of information on chemotherapy or minimally invasive treatment included in the SEER database, its effect on survival could not be evaluated. Second, as a retrospective registry assessment, this study has some intrinsic defects of a retrospective study. Third, due to the low incidence in young men with breast cancer, the sample size in our study is rather small. In fact, male breast cancer may be presented with more aggressive behavior and the lymph node metastasis rate ranges from 35% to 84%.<sup>[<xref rid="R29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>]</sup> Pitifully, some molecular characteristics affecting the prognosis of male patients with breast cancer were not analyzed in our study. Several studies have pointed that a significant number of patients (mostly BRCA2 mutation positive) developed multiple cancers including male breast cancer; most male cancers are ER positive but without a corresponding increase in PR positivity and only a weaker association with estrogen-controlled markers such as PS2, HSP27, and Cathepsin D; increased methylation defines a subset of familial male breast cancer and with average methylation index may be a useful prognostic marker.<sup>[<xref rid="R32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]</sup></p><p>In fact, some disputes can be discovered about the prognosis of young patients in all tumor types. For example, a study found that gastric cancer in young patients more aggressive; however, colorectal cancer had a better prognostic in young patients by another study demonstrated.<sup>[<xref rid="R35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>,<xref rid="R36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>]</sup> In our study, we analyzed the different clinical and pathologic factors and prognosis of young male breast cancer compared with old male breast cancer and young female breast cancer for the first time. And more relevant researches are needed.</p></sec><sec><title>Author contributions</title><p><bold>Data curation:</bold> Haiyong Wang, Hongju Zhang.</p><p><bold>Investigation:</bold> Xiaohui Wang.</p><p><bold>Methodology:</bold> Naikun Li.</p><p><bold>Software:</bold> Haiyong Wang.</p><p><bold>Supervision:</bold> Haiyong Wang.</p><p><bold>Validation:</bold> Haiyong Wang.</p><p><bold>Writing &#x02013; original draft:</bold> Naikun Li.</p><p><bold>Writing &#x02013; review &#x00026; editing:</bold> Haiyong Wang.</p></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Material</title><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="SD1"><caption><title>Supplemental Digital Content</title></caption><media mimetype="application" mime-subtype="pdf" xlink:href="medi-97-e12686-s001.docx" xlink:type="simple" id="d35e792" position="anchor"/></supplementary-material></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn fn-type="abbr"><p>Abbreviations: CI = confidence interval, CSS = cancer-specific survival, ER = estrogen receptor, HER-2 = human epidermal growth factor receptor 2, HR = hazard ratio, OS = over survival, PR = progesterone receptor, SEER = Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results.</p></fn><fn fn-type="supported-by"><p>This study was supported jointly by the China Postdoctoral Fund (no: 21300075311104) and Shandong Postdoctoral Innovation Special Fund (no: 201602012).</p></fn><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>Supplemental Digital Content is available for this article.</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="R1"><label>[1]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Siegel</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Naishadham</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Jemal</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Cancer statistics 2012</article-title>. <source>CA Cancer J Clin</source>
<year>2012</year>;<volume>62</volume>:<elocation-id>283</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>98</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22987332</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>[2]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hill</surname><given-names>TD</given-names></name><name><surname>Khamis</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Tyczynski</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Comparison of male and female breast cancer incidence trends, tumor characteristics, and survival</article-title>. <source>Ann Epidemiol</source>
<year>2005</year>;<volume>15</volume>:<elocation-id>773</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>80</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16257362</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>[3]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Giordano</surname><given-names>SH</given-names></name><name><surname>Cohen</surname><given-names>DS</given-names></name><name><surname>Buzdar</surname><given-names>AU</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Breast carcinoma in men: a population-based study</article-title>. <source>Cancer</source>
<year>2004</year>;<volume>101</volume>:<elocation-id>51</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>7</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15221988</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>[4]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Speirs</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name><surname>Shaaban</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>The rising incidence of male breast cancer</article-title>. <source>Breast Cancer Res Treat</source>
<year>2009</year>;<volume>115</volume>:<elocation-id>429</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>30</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18478326</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>[5]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ruddy</surname><given-names>KJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Winer</surname><given-names>EP</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Male breast cancer: risk factors, biology, diagnosis, treatment, and survivorship</article-title>. <source>Ann Oncol</source>
<year>2013</year>;<volume>24</volume>:<elocation-id>1434</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>43</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23425944</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>[6]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Foerster</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Foerster</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Wulff</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Matched-pair analysis of patients with female and male breast cancer: a comparative analysis</article-title>. <source>BMC Cancer</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>11</volume>:<elocation-id>335</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>48</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21816051</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>[7]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gnerlich</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Deshpande</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Jeffe</surname><given-names>DB</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Poorer survival outcomes for male breast cancer compared with female breast cancer may be attributable to in-stage migration</article-title>. <source>Ann Surg Oncol</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>18</volume>:<elocation-id>1837</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>44</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21484520</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>[8]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>XF</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>A prognostic analysis of male breast cancer (MALE BREAST CANCER) compared with post-menopausal female breast cancer (FEMALE BREAST CANCER)</article-title>. <source>PLoS One</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>10</volume>:<elocation-id>e0136670</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26313461</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>[9]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ademuyiwa</surname><given-names>FO</given-names></name><name><surname>Cyr</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Ivanovich</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Managing breast cancer in younger women: challenges and solutions</article-title>. <source>Breast Cancer (Dove Med Press)</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>8</volume>:<elocation-id>1</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>2</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26730210</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R10"><label>[10]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>RH</given-names></name><name><surname>Chien</surname><given-names>FL</given-names></name><name><surname>Bleyer</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Incidence of breast cancer with distant involvement among women in the United States, 1976 to 2009</article-title>. <source>JAMA</source>
<year>2013</year>;<volume>309</volume>:<elocation-id>800</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>5</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23443443</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R11"><label>[11]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bharat</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Aft</surname><given-names>RL</given-names></name><name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Patient and tumor characteristics associated with increased mortality in young women (&#x0003c; or = 40 years) with breast cancer</article-title>. <source>J Surg Oncol</source>
<year>2009</year>;<volume>100</volume>:<elocation-id>248</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>51</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19330813</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R12"><label>[12]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sheridan</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name><surname>Scott</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Caroline</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Breast cancer in young women: have the prognostic implications of breast cancer subtypes changed over time?</article-title>
<source>Breast Cancer Res Treat</source>
<year>2014</year>;<volume>147</volume>:<elocation-id>617</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>29</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25209005</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R13"><label>[13]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Copson</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Eccles</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Maishman</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Prospective observational study of breast cancer treatment outcomes for UK women aged 18-40 years at diagnosis: the POSH study</article-title>. <source>J Natl Cancer Inst</source>
<year>2013</year>;<volume>105</volume>:<elocation-id>978</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>88</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23723422</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R14"><label>[14]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>LC</given-names></name><name><surname>Marotti</surname><given-names>JD</given-names></name><name><surname>Gelber</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Pathologic features and molecular phenotype by patient age in a large cohort of young women with breast cancer</article-title>. <source>Breast Cancer Res Treat</source>
<year>2012</year>;<volume>131</volume>:<elocation-id>1061</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>6</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22080245</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R15"><label>[15]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><comment>Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results (SEER) Program (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.seer.cancer.gov/">www.seer.cancer.gov</ext-link>) SEER&#x02217;Stat Database: Incidence - SEER 18 Regs Research Data + Hurricane Katrina Impacted Louisiana Cases, Nov 2014 Sub (1973&#x02013;2012 varying) - Linked To County Attributes - Total US, 1969&#x02013;2013 Counties, National Cancer Institute, DCCPS, Surveillance Research Program, Surveillance Systems Branch, released April 2015, based on the November 2014 submission</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R16"><label>[16]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Kong</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Better survival in PMRT of female breast cancer patients with &#x0003e;5 negative lymph nodes: a population-based study</article-title>. <source>Medicine (Baltimore)</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>96</volume>:<elocation-id>e5998</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28121956</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R17"><label>[17]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Tong</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>He</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Clinicopathological characteristics and survival analysis of 87 male breast cancer cases</article-title>. <source>Breast Care (Basel)</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>6</volume>:<elocation-id>446</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>51</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22419898</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R18"><label>[18]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bourhafour</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Belbaraka</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Souadka</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Male breast cancer: a report of 127 cases at a Moroccan institution</article-title>. <source>BMC Res Notes</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>4</volume>:<elocation-id>219</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21714875</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R19"><label>[19]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name><name><surname>Saslow</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Sawyer</surname><given-names>KA</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>American Cancer Society guidelines for breast cancer screening: update 2003</article-title>. <source>CA Cancer J Clin</source>
<year>2003</year>;<volume>53</volume>:<elocation-id>141</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>69</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12809408</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R20"><label>[20]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Anderson</surname><given-names>WF</given-names></name><name><surname>Jatoi</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name><surname>Tse</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Male breast cancer: a population-based comparison with female breast cancer</article-title>. <source>J Clin Oncol</source>
<year>2010</year>;<volume>28</volume>:<elocation-id>232</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>9</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19996029</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R21"><label>[21]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang-Rodriguez</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Cross</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Gallagher</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Male breast carcinoma: correlation of ER, PR, Ki-67, Her2-Neu, and p53 with treatment and survival, a study of 65 cases</article-title>. <source>Mod Pathol</source>
<year>2002</year>;<volume>15</volume>:<elocation-id>853</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>86</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12181271</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R22"><label>[22]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Arslan</surname><given-names>UY</given-names></name><name><surname>Oks&#x000fc;zo&#x0011f;lu</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Ozdemir</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Outcome of non-metastatic male breast cancer: 118 patients</article-title>. <source>Med Oncol</source>
<year>2012</year>;<volume>29</volume>:<elocation-id>554</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>60</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21573973</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R23"><label>[23]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>JY</given-names></name><name><surname>Kachnic</surname><given-names>LA</given-names></name><name><surname>Hirsch</surname><given-names>AE</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>The impact of race in male breast cancer treatment and outcome in the United States: a population-based analysis of 4,279 patients</article-title>. <source>Int J Breast Cancer</source>
<year>2014</year>;<volume>2014</volume>:<elocation-id>685842</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25349739</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R24"><label>[24]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Dehal</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Abbas</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Johna</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Racial disparities in clinical presentation, surgical treatment and in-hospital outcomes of women with breast cancer: analysis of nationwide inpatient sample database</article-title>. <source>Breast Cancer Res Treat</source>
<year>2013</year>;<volume>139</volume>:<elocation-id>561</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>9</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23690143</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R25"><label>[25]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>LN</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>The prognostic value of clinical and pathologic features in nonmetastatic operable male breast cancer</article-title>. <source>Asian J Androl</source>
<year>2016</year>;<volume>18</volume>:<elocation-id>90</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>5</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25994649</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R26"><label>[26]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Clinicopathologic characteristics and survival of male breast cancer</article-title>. <source>Int J Clin Oncol</source>
<year>2014</year>;<volume>19</volume>:<elocation-id>280</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>7</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23640121</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R27"><label>[27]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fields</surname><given-names>EC</given-names></name><name><surname>DeWitt</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Fisher</surname><given-names>CM</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Management of male breast cancer in the United States: a surveillance, epidemiology and end results analysis</article-title>. <source>Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys</source>
<year>2013</year>;<volume>87</volume>:<elocation-id>747</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>52</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24138917</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R28"><label>[28]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nahleh</surname><given-names>ZA</given-names></name><name><surname>Srikantiah</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Safa</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Male breast cancer in the veterans affairs population: a comparative analysis</article-title>. <source>Cancer</source>
<year>2007</year>;<volume>109</volume>:<elocation-id>1471</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>7</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17342768</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R29"><label>[29]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>El Hajjam</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Khaiz</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Benider</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Cancer of the breast in men. Apropos of 50 cases</article-title>. <source>J Chir (Paris)</source>
<year>1995</year>;<volume>132</volume>:<elocation-id>131</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>6</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7782385</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R30"><label>[30]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></name><name><surname>Koo</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Clinicopathological characteristics of male breast cancer</article-title>. <source>Yonsei Med J</source>
<year>2008</year>;<volume>49</volume>:<elocation-id>978</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>86</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19108022</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R31"><label>[31]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rachid</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Yacouba</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Hassane</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Male breast cancer: 22 case reports at the National Hospital of Niamey-Niger (West Africa)</article-title>. <source>Pan Afr Med J</source>
<year>2009</year>;<volume>3</volume>:<elocation-id>15</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21532724</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R32"><label>[32]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fentiman</surname><given-names>IS</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>The biology of male breast cancer</article-title>. <source>Breast</source>
<year>2018</year>;<volume>38</volume>:<elocation-id>132</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>5</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29316513</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R33"><label>[33]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ibrahim</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Yadav</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Ogunleye</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Male BRCA mutation carriers: clinical characteristics and cancer spectrum</article-title>. <source>BMC Cancer</source>
<year>2018</year>;<volume>18</volume>:<elocation-id>179</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29433453</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R34"><label>[34]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Deb</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Gorringe</surname><given-names>KL</given-names></name><name><surname>Pang</surname><given-names>JB</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>BRCA2 carriers with male breast cancer show elevated tumour methylation</article-title>. <source>BMC Cancer</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>17</volume>:<elocation-id>641</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28893223</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R35"><label>[35]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gurzu</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Kadar</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Sugimura</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Gastric cancer in young vs old Romanian patients: immunoprofile with emphasis on maspin and mena protein reactivity</article-title>. <source>APMIS</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>123</volume>:<elocation-id>223</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>33</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25556597</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R36"><label>[36]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gurzu</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Aberrant pattern of the cytokeratin 7/cytokeratin 20 immunophenotype in colorectal adenocarcinomas with BRAF mutations</article-title>. <source>Pathol Res Pract</source>
<year>2012</year>;<volume>208</volume>:<elocation-id>163</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>6</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22361037</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>