<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD v1.1 20151215//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="review-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.3 20070202//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName journalpublishing.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.3?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName jp2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Medicine (Baltimore)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Medicine (Baltimore)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">MEDI</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Medicine</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0025-7974</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1536-5964</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Wolters Kluwer Health</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6133534</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">30095639</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">MD-D-17-06134</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000011790</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="art-access-id">11790</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="hwp-journal-coll"><subject>3500</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research Article</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title><italic>HLA-DRB1</italic> polymorphisms and alopecia areata disease risk</article-title><subtitle>A systematic review and meta-analysis</subtitle></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Ji</surname><given-names>Conghua</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>a</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Shan</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>a</sup></xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp"><sup>&#x02217;</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>Kan</given-names></name><degrees>PhD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>b</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>Hongbin</given-names></name><degrees>MD, PhD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3"><sup>c</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Qiushuang</given-names></name><degrees>PharM</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>a</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Ying</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>a</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Sijia</given-names></name><degrees>BM</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>a</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Qing</given-names></name><degrees>PhD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff4"><sup>d</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>Yi</given-names></name><degrees>MD, PhD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3"><sup>c</sup></xref></contrib></contrib-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="editor"><name><surname>Comim.</surname><given-names>Fabio</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1"><label>a</label>Center of Clinical Evaluation, Zhejiang Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, China</aff><aff id="aff2"><label>b</label>Institute for Regenerative Cures, Department of Dermatology, University of California Davis School of Medicine, Sacramento, CA, USA</aff><aff id="aff3"><label>c</label>Department of Dermatology, Zhejiang Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Hangzhou, Zhejiang</aff><aff id="aff4"><label>d</label>Department of Epidemiology, School of Public Health, Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, Guangdong, China.</aff><author-notes id="cor1"><corresp><label>&#x02217;</label>Correspondence: Shan Liu, Center of Clinical Evaluation, Zhejiang Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, No.54 Youdian Road, Shangcheng District, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, China (e-mail: <email>graystar92@163.com</email>)</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>8</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>10</day><month>8</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><volume>97</volume><issue>32</issue><elocation-id>e11790</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>3</day><month>10</month><year>2017</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>16</day><month>7</month><year>2018</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2018 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2018</copyright-year><license license-type="open-access" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0"><license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License 4.0, which allows others to remix, tweak, and build upon the work, even for commercial purposes, as long as the author is credited and the new creations are licensed under the identical terms. <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</ext-link></license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="medi-97-e11790.pdf"/><abstract abstract-type="toc"><p>Supplemental Digital Content is available in the text</p></abstract><abstract><title>Abstract</title><sec sec-type="background"><title>Background:</title><p>Published studies have reported conflicting and heterogeneous results regarding the association between human leukocyte antigen (<italic>HLA</italic>)-<italic>DRB1</italic> polymorphisms and alopecia areata (AA). This study aimed to review and quantitatively analyze the association between <italic>HLA</italic>-<italic>DRB1</italic> polymorphisms and AA.</p></sec><sec sec-type="methods"><title>Methods:</title><p>In this study, all relevant publications were searched through December 2016. Odds ratios (ORs) and confidence intervals (CIs) for comparisons between case and control groups were calculated. Stata 14.0 software was used to perform statistical analysis. This research does not require formal ethical approval because the data used in this analysis do not involve personal information and thus do not affect privacy.</p></sec><sec sec-type="results"><title>Results:</title><p>Twelve articles were identified. For <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;04</italic> and <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;16</italic> polymorphisms, the OR (95% CIs) was 1.49 (1.24&#x02013;1.78) and 1.61 (1.08&#x02013;2.41), and <italic>P</italic> was &#x0003c;.01 and &#x0003c;.01, respectively. For <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;0301, HLA-DRB1&#x02217;09</italic>, and <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;13</italic> polymorphisms, the OR (95% CIs) was 0.42 (0.28&#x02013;0.63), 0.74 (0.55&#x02013;0.99), and 0.62 (0.40&#x02013;0.98), and <italic>P</italic> was &#x0003c;.01, &#x0003c;.01, and &#x0003c;.01, respectively. Statistical evidence revealed no publication bias (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003e;&#x0200a;.05).</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusion"><title>Conclusion:</title><p>The present meta-analysis suggested that <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;04</italic> and <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;16</italic> polymorphisms might be associated with increased AA risk, while <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;0301</italic>, <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;09</italic>, and <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;13</italic> polymorphisms might decrease the AA risk. Studies with adequate methodological quality on gene&#x02013;gene and gene&#x02013;environment interactions are needed to validate the results in the future.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group><title>Keywords</title><kwd>alopecia areata</kwd><kwd><italic>DRB1</italic></kwd><kwd>human leukocyte antigen</kwd><kwd>odds ratio</kwd><kwd>polymorphism</kwd><kwd>risk</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>OPEN-ACCESS</meta-name><meta-value>TRUE</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec><label>1</label><title>Introduction</title><p>Alopecia areata (AA) is a cell-mediated autoimmune disease causing an unpredictable hair loss with no overt epidermal changes. The lifetime risk of AA is estimated to be 1.7%. It affects both sexes and people of all races, but is more prevalent in children.<sup>[<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]</sup> In AA, abnormal immune damage leads to round or oval patches, which may advance to all scalp hair (alopecia totalis) or all body hair (alopecia universalis).<sup>[<xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]</sup></p><p>Human leukocyte antigen (HLA)-<italic>DRB1</italic> polymorphisms have been discussed in many types of autoimmune diseases, for instance, aplastic anemia,<sup>[<xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]</sup> systemic lupus erythematosus and lupus nephritis,<sup>[<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]</sup> Vogt&#x02013;Koyanagi&#x02013;Harada disease,<sup>[<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]</sup> and multiple sclerosis.<sup>[<xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]</sup> As one of the autoimmune diseases which caused by several major susceptibility genes, AA is genetically associated with alleles of HLA in different ethnic groups.<sup>[<xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]</sup> CD4+ lymphocytes play an important role in AA inflammatory processes. They have been proposed to recognize the antigen and major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class II complexes on macrophages and Langerhans cells, and the expression may be induced on other nucleated cells, leading to AA.<sup>[<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,<xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]</sup> It is noticed that <italic>HLA-DR</italic> and <italic>HLA-DQ</italic> alleles are responsible for presenting the antigen to CD4+ T cells.<sup>[<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</sup></p><p>One genome-wide association study (GWAS) discussed the relationship between HLA and AA.<sup>[<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]</sup> It revealed HLA-DR as a key etiologic driver. The study indicated <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;04:01</italic> polymorphisms as the potential risk factor for AA (OR&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;1.64). GWAS explored the genetic architecture of complex diseases, but was limited in detecting any other kinds of genetic variants such as deletions associated with a high percentage of autoimmune diseases.<sup>[<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]</sup></p><p>Previous individual studies have been concerned with the association between <italic>HLA-DRB1</italic> polymorphisms and AA. Three studies indicated <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;04</italic> allele as a risk factor for the development of AA.<sup>[<xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]</sup> However, the results were inconsistent with the findings of other studies.<sup>[<xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup> Moreover, one study suggested a lower occurrence of <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;15</italic> polymorphisms in AA,<sup>[<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</sup> whereas others found no association.<sup>[<xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,<xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup></p><p>A number of conflicting studies have reported the relationship between <italic>HLA-DRB1</italic> polymorphisms and AA risk in small samples,<sup>[<xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]</sup> but no definite consensus existed. Therefore, this meta-analysis aimed to examine the relationship between <italic>HLA-DRB1</italic> polymorphisms and AA. Since a single study might have been underpowered to clarify the genes with AA risk, the purpose of this study was to increase the statistical power and evaluate the evidence from studies by summarizing it quantitatively with a meta-analytic approach.</p></sec><sec><label>2</label><title>Materials and methods</title><p>This study was performed following the standards of the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-analyses (PRISMA) criteria<sup>[<xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]</sup> (Supplemental Table 1) and the recommendations of the Cochrane Collaboration.<sup>[<xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]</sup> A protocol for this systematic review has been published in PROSPERO with the registration number CRD42015023718 (Supplemental File 1).</p><sec><label>2.1</label><title>Search strategy</title><p>We carried out an electronic search of multiple databases, including PubMed, Embase, Cochrane database, Chinese China National Knowledge Infrastructure, Chinese Biomedical Literature Database, Wang Fang, and Chinese Social Sciences Citation Index, through December 2016 for all studies on the association between HLA polymorphisms and AA by using the following keywords (&#x0201c;Alopecia areata&#x0201d; or &#x0201c;nonscarring hair loss&#x0201d; or &#x0201c;ophiasis&#x0201d; or &#x0201c;alopecia celsi&#x0201d; or &#x0201c;alopecia universalis&#x0201d; or &#x0201c;alopecia totalis&#x0201d;) and (&#x0201c;human leukocyte antigen&#x0201d; or &#x0201c;HLA&#x0201d; or &#x0201c;major histocompatibility complex&#x0201d; or &#x0201c;DRB1&#x0201d; or &#x0201c;MHC&#x0201d;) (Supplemental Table 2). No language restrictions were imposed in this research. We also searched the references of the included studies and e-mailed the study authors to identify additional studies and collect missing data.</p></sec><sec><label>2.2</label><title>Inclusion and exclusion criteria</title><p>The inclusion criteria were as follows: studies concerned with the association between <italic>HLA-DRB1</italic> polymorphisms and AA; and sufficient data on odds ratio (OR) with a 95% confidence interval (CI).</p><p>The exclusion criteria were as follows: reviews, comments, editorials, or basic science or animal studies; genotype frequency not revealed or the relevant data not obtained by contacting authors; and duplicate studies.</p></sec><sec><label>2.3</label><title>Study selection</title><p>Two review authors initially screened the titles and abstracts independently. The full text versions of any studies of potential relevance were retrieved and examined carefully according to inclusion and exclusion criteria. Only the most recent study was included when there were overlapping data or even repeating data. Any discrepancies were adjudicated by regular conferences involving the third reviewer (Prof Chen). She downloaded the full text of the inconsistent studies and discussed step by step according to the inclusion and exclusion criteria.</p></sec><sec><label>2.4</label><title>Data extraction</title><p>Data extraction was performed independently by 2 investigators using a predetermined extraction form. The third participant was consulted for discussion to reach an agreement concerning discrepancies. The following items were extracted from each study: first author's last name, publication year, country, the Newcastle-Ottawa Scale (NOS), numbers of cases and controls, gene detection method, genes involved, and frequency of <italic>HLA-DRB1</italic> alleles.</p></sec><sec><label>2.5</label><title>Quality assessment for individual studies</title><p>A scoring system based on the NOS was used to determine the quality of each study. Items assessed included selection, comparability of cases/controls, and exposure. The score of overall quality ranged from 0 to 9. The NOS score was divided into 3 levels (high quality, score &#x02265;7; moderate quality, 4&#x0200a;&#x02264;&#x0200a;score&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;7; low quality, score &#x0003e;4). Disagreements were settled as described earlier.</p></sec><sec><label>2.6</label><title>Statistical analysis</title><p>All statistical analyses were conducted using Stata 14.0 (Stata Corporation, TX). Dichotomous data were reported as OR (calculated by the <italic>&#x003c7;</italic><sup>2</sup> test). The pooled ORs and the 95% CIs used for assessing the strength of association were determined by the <italic>Z</italic> test. Heterogeneity across studies was checked by the Cochran <italic>Q</italic> statistic and the <italic>I</italic><sup>2</sup> test.<sup>[<xref rid="R26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]</sup> If a 2-sided <italic>P</italic> value &#x0003c;.05 was considered as statistically significant, then a random-effects model was used (shown as &#x0201c;D&#x0200a;+&#x0200a;L&#x0201d;).<sup>[<xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>]</sup> Otherwise, a fixed-effects model was applied (shown as &#x0201c;M-H&#x0201d;).<sup>[<xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]</sup> When <italic>I</italic><sup>2</sup> was &#x0003e;50% indicating high heterogeneity, subgroup analyses were used. Subgroup analyses were performed by area to reveal whether it could lead to heterogeneity. Meta-regression was used to reveal whether continent, country, or NOS score could lead to heterogeneity.</p><p>A sensitivity analysis was performed by sequential omission of individual studies to evaluate the stability of outcomes.<sup>[<xref rid="R29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]</sup> Harbord<sup>[<xref rid="R30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>]</sup> and Egger<sup>[<xref rid="R31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>]</sup> tests were conducted to evaluate the publication bias with a <italic>P</italic> value &#x0003c;.05 for considering statistical significance. If publication bias was indicated with statistical significance, a trim-and-fill analysis was performed.<sup>[<xref rid="R32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>]</sup></p></sec></sec><sec><label>3</label><title>Results</title><sec><label>3.1</label><title>Study characteristics</title><p>We conducted this study under PRISMA statement (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">1</xref>). Through literature searches, 626 studies discussed the association of HLA polymorphism and AA. After reading titles and abstracts, 22 studies were identified. Unfortunately, 10 articles were eliminated due to some reasons. The Supplemental Table 3 lists the reasons for the exclusion of these studies. Finally, 12 studies<sup>[<xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]</sup> consisting 1283 cases and 32,343 controls were included, 2 of which were graduation theses of postgraduate students.<sup>[<xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,<xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]</sup> Zhang et al<sup>[<xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]</sup> included 121 cases and 24,930 controls, which accounted for huge different sample sizes in 2 groups. Table <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">1</xref> lists the included studies and their main characteristics. These studies covered Europe, Asia, America, and Africa. The average NOS score was 5.08, which revealed that the methodological quality was of average level (Table <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">1</xref> and Supplemental Table 4). Of the 12 studies, 2 were of high quality<sup>[<xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,<xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]</sup> and 10 of moderate quality<sup>[<xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,<xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,<xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]</sup> (Supplemental Table 4).</p><fig id="F1" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Flow diagram of the study selection process.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-g001"/></fig><table-wrap id="T1" position="float"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Characteristics of studies included in the meta-analysis.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-g002"/></table-wrap></sec><sec><label>3.2</label><title>Quantitative synthesis</title><p>Table <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">2</xref> lists the main results of the meta-analysis. In total, 13 <italic>HLA-DRB1</italic> allele families and 1 specific allele were extracted from the studies to investigate their relationships to AA.</p><table-wrap id="T2" position="float"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Meta-analysis of associations between <italic>HLA-DRB1</italic> alleles and alopecia areata.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-g003"/></table-wrap><p>Two allele families (<italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;04</italic> and <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;16</italic>) conferred a significantly increased risk. For <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;04</italic> polymorphisms, the analysis of the pooled data of 8 case-control studies<sup>[<xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup> revealed a significant increase in frequency (31.6% compared with 22.2% in controls), with an evidence of heterogeneity (<italic>I</italic><sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;43.0%, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.081). A random-effects model was used for calculating OR. Overall OR (95% CIs) was 1.49 (1.24&#x02013;1.78) with <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;0.01 (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">2</xref>). For <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;16</italic> polymorphisms, the analysis of the pooled data of 4 case-control studies revealed a significant increase in frequency (12.0% compared with 6.0% in controls), with no evidence of heterogeneity (<italic>I</italic><sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0.0%, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.600). A fixed-effects model was used for calculating OR. Overall OR (95% CIs) was 1.60 (1.07&#x02013;2.39) with <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.05 (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">3</xref>).</p><fig id="F2" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>Forest plot of HLA-DRB1&#x02217;04 polymorphism and alopecia areata.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-g004"/></fig><fig id="F3" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>Forest plot of HLA-DRB1&#x02217;16 polymorphism and alopecia areata.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-g005"/></fig><p><italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;0301</italic>, <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;09</italic>, and <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;13</italic> polymorphisms conferred a significant protective effect for AA. A low heterogeneity for <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;0301</italic> (<italic>I</italic><sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;36.2%, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.211), <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;09</italic> (<italic>I</italic><sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0%, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.441), and <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;13</italic> (<italic>I</italic><sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;53.9%, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.043) polymorphisms was observed. A fixed-effects model was used for calculating OR for <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;0301</italic>,<italic>&#x02217;09</italic> and a random-effects model was used for calculating OR for <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;13</italic>. The OR (95% CIs) was 0.42 (0.28&#x02013;0.63) for <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;0301</italic> (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F4">4</xref>), 0.74 (0.55&#x02013;0.99) for <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;09</italic> (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F5">5</xref>), and 0.62 (0.40&#x02013;0.98) for <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;13</italic> polymorphisms (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F6">6</xref>).</p><fig id="F4" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>Forest plot of HLA-DRB1&#x02217;0301 polymorphism and alopecia areata.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-g006"/></fig><fig id="F5" position="float"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>Forest plot of HLA-DRB1&#x02217;09 polymorphism and alopecia areata.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-g007"/></fig><fig id="F6" position="float"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>Forest plot of HLA-DRB1&#x02217;13 polymorphism and alopecia areata.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-g008"/></fig><p>For <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;01</italic>, <italic>DRB1&#x02217;03</italic>, <italic>DRB1&#x02217;07</italic>, <italic>DRB1&#x02217;08</italic>, <italic>DRB1&#x02217;10</italic>, <italic>DRB1&#x02217;11</italic>, <italic>DRB1&#x02217;12</italic>, <italic>DRB1&#x02217;14</italic>, <italic>DRB1&#x02217;15</italic>, and <italic>DRB1&#x02217;15/16</italic> alleles, no evidence of association in statistics between <italic>HLA-DRB1</italic> polymorphisms and AA was found (Table <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">2</xref> and Supplemental File 2).</p></sec><sec><label>3.3</label><title>Subgroup analysis</title><p>The subgroup analysis was conducted on <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;03</italic>, <italic>DRB1&#x02217;07</italic>, <italic>DRB1&#x02217;08</italic>, <italic>DRB1&#x02217;11</italic>, and <italic>DRB1&#x02217;15</italic> polymorphisms. For <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;03</italic> polymorphisms, the analysis of the pooled data of 5 case-control studies revealed low heterogeneity in the Europe subgroup (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.192). A fixed-effects model was used for calculating OR. Overall OR (95% CIs) was 0.40 (0.26&#x02013;0.60) with <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.01 (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F7">7</xref>). For <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;08</italic>, a low heterogeneity was observed in the Asia subgroup (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.854). Overall OR (95% CIs) was 0.58 (0.36&#x02013;0.93) with <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;.01 (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F8">8</xref>). However, no evidence of association in statistics was found between <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;15</italic> (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F9">9</xref>), <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;07</italic> (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F10">10</xref>), and <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;11</italic> (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F11">11</xref>) polymorphisms and AA in the subgroup analysis.</p><fig id="F7" position="float"><label>Figure 7</label><caption><p>Forest plot of HLA-DRB1&#x02217;03 polymorphism and alopecia areata.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-g009"/></fig><fig id="F8" position="float"><label>Figure 8</label><caption><p>Forest plot of HLA-DRB1&#x02217;08 polymorphism and alopecia areata.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-g010"/></fig><fig id="F9" position="float"><label>Figure 9</label><caption><p>Forest plot of HLA-DRB1&#x02217;15 polymorphism and alopecia areata.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-g011"/></fig><fig id="F10" position="float"><label>Figure 10</label><caption><p>Forest plot of HLA-DRB1&#x02217;07 polymorphism and alopecia areata.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-g012"/></fig><fig id="F11" position="float"><label>Figure 11</label><caption><p>Forest plot of HLA-DRB1&#x02217;11 polymorphism and alopecia areata.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-g013"/></fig></sec><sec><label>3.4</label><title>Sensitivity analyses</title><p>A single report involved in the meta-analysis was removed each time to reflect the influence of the individual dataset on the pooled OR. A significant deviation was detected in the study by Tao<sup>[<xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]</sup> when analyzing the association between <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;16</italic> polymorphisms and AA. After the exclusion of this study, heterogeneity decreased from 92.4% (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F12">12</xref>) to 0% (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">3</xref>). The trim-and-fill analysis suggested that no studies (comparisons) were missing from the dataset. It turned out that <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;16</italic> polymorphisms conferred a significantly increased risk (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">3</xref>).</p><fig id="F12" position="float"><label>Figure 12</label><caption><p>Forest plot of HLA-DRB1&#x02217;16<sup>#</sup> polymorphism and alopecia areata.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-g014"/></fig><p>For others, the corresponding pooled ORs were not materially changed (data not shown), indicating that the results were statistically robust.</p></sec><sec><label>3.5</label><title>Publication bias</title><p>Harbord and Eggers tests were not significant in any comparison (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003e;&#x0200a;.05, shown in Table <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">2</xref>). The shape of the funnel plot was relatively symmetric for most alleles (Supplemental File 3). They all indicated a low probability of publication bias.</p></sec><sec><label>3.6</label><title>Influence of continent, country, and NOS score</title><p>The results of meta-regression analysis showed that continent, country, or NOS score did not account for heterogeneity (Table <xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">3</xref>).</p><table-wrap id="T3" position="float"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>Meta-regression.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-g015"/></table-wrap></sec></sec><sec><label>4</label><title>Discussion</title><p>A comprehensive evaluation is provided by this systematic review to find out the relationship of <italic>HLA-DRB1</italic> polymorphisms with AA. According to inclusion and exclusion criteria, a total of 1283 cases and 32,343 controls from 12 case-control studies<sup>[<xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]</sup> were selected and analyzed. The present study revealed that <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;04</italic> and <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;16</italic> polymorphisms might be associated with increased AA risk, while <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;0301</italic>, <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;0</italic>9, and <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;13</italic> polymorphisms might decrease the AA risk.</p><p>The associations between HLA polymorphisms and AA risk have been intensively studied.<sup>[<xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]</sup> For HLA-<italic>DRB1&#x02217;04</italic> polymorphisms, 5 of 8 studies indicated that OR &#x0003e;1 but the 95% CIs cross 1. First, a single study with limited sample size might have been underpowered to clarify the genes with AA risk. Second, a single study can only represent one ethnic background. So after summarizing it quantitatively with a meta-analytic approach, the pooled results indicated that HLA-<italic>DRB1&#x02217;04</italic> polymorphisms might be potential risk factors for AA (OR&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;1.49, Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">2</xref>). A similar situation occurs when analyzing the association of <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;09, HLA-DRB1&#x02217;16</italic>, and <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;13</italic> polymorphisms with AA. The purpose of this study was to increase the statistical power, evaluate the evidence from studies by summarizing it quantitatively with a meta-analytic approach, and get a reliable conclusion.</p><p>One genome-wide meta-analysis discussed the relationship between HLA and AA.<sup>[<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]</sup> The study indicated <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;04:01</italic> polymorphisms as the potential risk factors for AA (OR&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;1.64). It included 2489 cases and 5287 controls from the United States and Central Europe. Many studies implied that ethnic difference might be associated with the genotype distribution. Besides the United States and Europe, the present study included Asian and African countries. The results revealed that <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;04</italic> polymorphisms might be a risk factor for AA, which is a supplement of the previous meta-analyses.</p><p>Heterogeneity could potentially impact the results of all meta-analyses.<sup>[<xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]</sup> In our research, statistical heterogeneity was noticed among some analyses. We therefore explored the sources of heterogeneity to examine whether the results were robust. First, we have conducted meta-regression analysis to reveal whether continent, country, or NOS score could lead to heterogeneity. However, meta-regression indicated that these covariates were not statistically significant (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003e;&#x0200a;.05). Second, sensitivity analyses were performed. It indicated that after the exclusion of the study by Tao,<sup>[<xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]</sup> heterogeneity decreased from 92.4% (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F12">12</xref>) to 0% (Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">3</xref>) when studying the association of <italic>HLA</italic>-<italic>DRB1&#x02217;16</italic> polymorphisms with AA. Additionally, subgroup analyses revealed that geographical factors might have led to the heterogeneity when studying the association of <italic>HLA</italic>-<italic>DRB1&#x02217;03</italic> and <italic>HLA</italic>-<italic>DRB1&#x02217;08</italic> polymorphisms with AA. However, because of the limited studies included in the subgroup analyses, further studies and analyses are needed to validate the findings.</p><p>To avoid local literature bias,<sup>[<xref rid="R33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>]</sup> we obtained and included both English and Chinese language reports. And yet, some shortcomings of the analysis could not be neglected. First, the number of included studies was limited because the incidence of <italic>HLA-DRB1</italic> genotypes was low. Enough information could not be obtained on clinical type and magnitude for subgroup analysis due to the limited number of included studies. Second, it was uncertain whether the cases were comparably representative, although significant publication bias between studies was not detected.</p></sec><sec><label>5</label><title>Conclusion</title><p>The present study revealed that <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;04</italic> and <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;16</italic> polymorphisms might be associated with increased AA risk, while <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;0301</italic>, <italic>HLA-DRB1&#x02217;09, HLA-DRB1&#x02217;13</italic> polymorphisms might decrease the AA risk. Studies with adequate methodological quality on gene&#x02013;gene and gene&#x02013;environment interactions are needed to validate the results in the future.</p></sec><sec><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>The authors sincerely thank all the authors of the original articles.</p></sec><sec><title>Author contributions</title><p><bold>Funding acquisition:</bold> Conghua Ji, Shan Liu.</p><p><bold>Methodology:</bold> Conghua Ji, Shan Liu.</p><p><bold>Project administration:</bold> Conghua Ji, Shan Liu.</p><p><bold>Writing &#x02013; original draft:</bold> Conghua Ji.</p><p><bold>Resources:</bold> Shan Liu, Kan Zhu, Qing Chen.</p><p><bold>Supervision:</bold> Shan Liu, Yi Cao.</p><p><bold>Validation:</bold> Shan Liu, Kan Zhu, Qing Chen.</p><p><bold>Writing &#x02013; review and editing:</bold> Shan Liu, Yi Cao.</p><p><bold>Investigation:</bold> Kan Zhu, Hongbin Luo, Qiushuang Li.</p><p><bold>Data curation:</bold> Hongbin Luo, Qiushuang Li.</p><p><bold>Formal analysis:</bold> Hongbin Luo, Ying Zhang.</p><p><bold>Software:</bold> Ying Zhang, Sijia Huang.</p><p><bold>Visualization:</bold> Sijia Huang.</p><p><bold>Conceptualization:</bold> Yi Cao.</p></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Material</title><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="SD1"><caption><title>Supplemental Digital Content</title></caption><media mimetype="application" mime-subtype="pdf" xlink:href="medi-97-e11790-s001.pdf" xlink:type="simple" id="d35e1320" position="anchor"/></supplementary-material></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn fn-type="abbr"><p>Abbreviations: AA = alopecia areata, CI = confidence interval, CNKI = Cochrane Library China National Knowledge Infrastructure, HLA = human leukocyte antigen, NOS = Newcastle-Ottawa Scale, OR = odds ratio, PRISMA = Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses.</p></fn><fn fn-type="supported-by"><p>This study was supported by the Administration of Traditional Chinese Medicine of Zhejiang Province, China (No. 2016ZA084), and the State Administration of Traditional Chinese Medicine of the People's Republic of China (No. JDZX2012172).</p></fn><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p>The authors declare no competing financial interests.</p></fn><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p>The authors have no conflict of interests.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>Supplemental Digital Content is available for this article.</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="R1"><label>[1]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Betz</surname><given-names>RC</given-names></name><name><surname>Petukhova</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Ripke</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Genome-wide meta-analysis in alopecia areata resolves HLA associations and reveals two new susceptibility loci</article-title>. <source>Nat Commun</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>6</volume>:<elocation-id>5966</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25608926</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>[2]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Olsen</surname><given-names>EA</given-names></name><name><surname>Hordinsky</surname><given-names>MK</given-names></name><name><surname>Price</surname><given-names>VH</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Alopecia areata investigational assessment guidelines&#x02013;Part II. National Alopecia Areata Foundation</article-title>. <source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source>
<year>2004</year>;<volume>51</volume>:<elocation-id>440</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>7</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15337988</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>[3]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Association of Human Leukocyte Antigen DRB1&#x02217;15 and DRB1&#x02217;15:01 polymorphisms with response to immunosuppressive therapy in patients with aplastic anemia: a meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>PLoS One</source>
<year>2016</year>;<volume>11</volume>:<elocation-id>e0162382</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27611583</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>[4]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Niu</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Tong</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Value of HLA-DR genotype in systemic lupus erythematosus and lupus nephritis: a meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>Int J Rheum Dis</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>18</volume>:<elocation-id>17</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>28</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25546242</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>[5]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Lv</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Association of HLA-DR4/HLA-DRB1&#x02217;04 with Vogt-Koyanagi-Harada disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>Sci Rep</source>
<year>2014</year>;<volume>4</volume>:<elocation-id>6887</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25382027</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>[6]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Ye</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>A meta-analysis of interaction between Epstein-Barr virus and HLA-DRB1&#x02217;1501 on risk of multiple sclerosis</article-title>. <source>Sci Rep</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>5</volume>:<elocation-id>18083</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26656273</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>[7]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Islam</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Leung</surname><given-names>PSC</given-names></name><name><surname>Huntley</surname><given-names>AC</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>The autoimmune basis of alopecia areata: a comprehensive review</article-title>. <source>Autoimmun Rev</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>14</volume>:<elocation-id>81</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>9</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25315746</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>[8]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Brocker</surname><given-names>EB</given-names></name><name><surname>Echternacht-Happle</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Hamm</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Abnormal expression of class I and class II major histocompatibility antigens in alopecia areata: modulation by topical immunotherapy</article-title>. <source>J Invest Dermatol</source>
<year>1987</year>;<volume>88</volume>:<elocation-id>564</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>8</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3471816</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>[9]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Messenger</surname><given-names>AG</given-names></name><name><surname>Bleehen</surname><given-names>SS</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Expression of HLA-DR by anagen hair follicles in alopecia areata</article-title>. <source>J Invest Dermatol</source>
<year>1985</year>;<volume>85</volume>:<elocation-id>569</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>72</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2415641</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R10"><label>[10]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Alzolibani</surname><given-names>AA</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Epidemiologic and genetic characteristics of alopecia areata (part 1)</article-title>. <source>Acta Dermatovenerol Alp Pannonica Adriat</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>20</volume>:<elocation-id>191</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>8</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22367375</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R11"><label>[11]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Golan</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Lander</surname><given-names>ES</given-names></name><name><surname>Rosset</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Measuring missing heritability: inferring the contribution of common variants</article-title>. <source>Proc Natl Acad Sci USA</source>
<year>2014</year>;<volume>111</volume>:<elocation-id>E5272</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>81</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25422463</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R12"><label>[12]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Entz</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Blaumeiser</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Betz</surname><given-names>RC</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Investigation of the HLA-DRB1 locus in alopecia areata</article-title>. <source>Eur J Dermatol</source>
<year>2006</year>;<volume>16</volume>:<elocation-id>363</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>7</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16935791</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R13"><label>[13]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><comment>Tao H. Association of severe Alopecia Areata and HLA-DRB1 alleles in Southern Chinese Han. Guangzhou Medical Colleage; 2011</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R14"><label>[14]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><comment>Qi S. Association of HLA-DRBl&#x02217;03, &#x02217;04 and &#x02217;11 alleles with alopecia areata in Han people in Eastern China. Fudan University; 2009</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R15"><label>[15]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Akar</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Orkunoglu</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Sengul</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>HLA class II alleles in patients with alopecia areata</article-title>. <source>Eur J Dermatol</source>
<year>2002</year>;<volume>12</volume>:<elocation-id>236</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>9</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11978563</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R16"><label>[16]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Attia</surname><given-names>EA</given-names></name><name><surname>El Shennawy</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Sefin</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Serum Interleukin-4 and total immunoglobulin E in nonatopic alopecia areata patients and HLA-DRB1 typing</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Res Pract</source>
<year>2010</year>;<volume>2010</volume>:<elocation-id>503587</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20671941</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R17"><label>[17]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Broniarczyk-Dyla</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Prusinska-Bratos</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Dubla-Berner</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>The protective role of the HLA-DR locus in patients with various clinical types of alopecia areata</article-title>. <source>Arch Immunol Therap Exp</source>
<year>2002</year>;<volume>50</volume>:<elocation-id>333</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>6</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R18"><label>[18]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Megiorni</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Pizzuti</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Mora</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Genetic association of HLA-DQB1 and HLA-DRB1 polymorphisms with alopecia areata in the Italian population</article-title>. <source>Br J Dermatol</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>165</volume>:<elocation-id>823</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>7</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21692766</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R19"><label>[19]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Polymorphism analysis of HLA-A,B and DRB1 in patients with alopecia areata</article-title>. <source>Int J Blood Transfus Hematol</source>
<year>2010</year>;<volume>33</volume>:<elocation-id>289</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>92</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R20"><label>[20]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Barbosa</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name><name><surname>Prestes-Carneiro</surname><given-names>LE</given-names></name><name><surname>Sobral</surname><given-names>AR</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Lack of association between alopecia areata and HLA class I and II in a southeastern Brazilian population</article-title>. <source>An Bras Dermatol</source>
<year>2016</year>;<volume>91</volume>:<elocation-id>284</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>9</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27438193</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R21"><label>[21]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Aliagaoglu</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Pirim</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name><surname>Atasoy</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Association between alopecia areata and HLA class I and II in Turkey</article-title>. <source>J Dermatol</source>
<year>2005</year>;<volume>32</volume>:<elocation-id>711</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>4</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16361713</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R22"><label>[22]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Barahmani</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>de Andrade</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Slusser</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Human leukocyte antigen class II alleles are associated with risk of alopecia areata</article-title>. <source>J Invest Dermatol</source>
<year>2008</year>;<volume>128</volume>:<elocation-id>240</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>3</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17637820</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R23"><label>[23]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Marques Da Costa</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Dupont</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Van Der Cruys</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Earlier occurrence of severe alopecia areata in HLA-DRB1&#x02217;11-positive patients</article-title>. <source>Dermatology</source>
<year>2006</year>;<volume>213</volume>:<elocation-id>12</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>4</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16778420</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R24"><label>[24]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Knobloch</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name><name><surname>Vogt</surname><given-names>PM</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses (PRISMA) statement and publication bias</article-title>. <source>J Craniomaxillofac Surg</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>39</volume>:<elocation-id>91</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>2</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21145753</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R25"><label>[25]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bero</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Rennie</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group>
<collab>The Cochrane Collaboration</collab>. <article-title>Preparing, maintaining, and disseminating systematic reviews of the effects of health care</article-title>. <source>JAMA</source>
<year>1995</year>;<volume>274</volume>:<elocation-id>1935</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>8</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8568988</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R26"><label>[26]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>SG</given-names></name><name><surname>Deeks</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses</article-title>. <source>BMJ</source>
<year>2003</year>;<volume>327</volume>:<elocation-id>557</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>60</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12958120</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R27"><label>[27]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>DerSimonian</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Laird</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Meta-analysis in clinical trials</article-title>. <source>Control Clin Trials</source>
<year>1986</year>;<volume>7</volume>:<elocation-id>177</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>88</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3802833</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R28"><label>[28]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mantel</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Haenszel</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Statistical aspects of the analysis of data from retrospective studies of disease</article-title>. <source>J Natl Cancer Inst</source>
<year>1959</year>;<volume>22</volume>:<elocation-id>719</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>48</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13655060</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R29"><label>[29]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Patsopoulos</surname><given-names>NA</given-names></name><name><surname>Evangelou</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Ioannidis</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Sensitivity of between-study heterogeneity in meta-analysis: proposed metrics and empirical evaluation</article-title>. <source>Int J Epidemiol</source>
<year>2008</year>;<volume>37</volume>:<elocation-id>1148</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>57</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18424475</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R30"><label>[30]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Harbord</surname><given-names>RM</given-names></name><name><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Sterne</surname><given-names>JAC</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Updated tests for small-study effects in meta-analyses</article-title>. <source>Stata J</source>
<year>2009</year>;<volume>9</volume>:<elocation-id>197</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>210</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R31"><label>[31]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Egger</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Davey Smith</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Schneider</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test</article-title>. <source>BMJ</source>
<year>1997</year>;<volume>315</volume>:<elocation-id>629</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>34</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9310563</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R32"><label>[32]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Weinhandl</surname><given-names>ED</given-names></name><name><surname>Duval</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Generalization of trim and fill for application in meta-regression</article-title>. <source>Res Synth Methods</source>
<year>2012</year>;<volume>3</volume>:<elocation-id>51</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>67</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26061999</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R33"><label>[33]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Trikalinos</surname><given-names>TA</given-names></name><name><surname>Kavvoura</surname><given-names>FK</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Local literature bias in genetic epidemiology: an empirical evaluation of the Chinese literature</article-title>. <source>PLoS Med</source>
<year>2005</year>;<volume>2</volume>:<elocation-id>e334</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16285839</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>