<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD v1.1 20151215//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.3 20070202//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName journalpublishing.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.3?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName jp2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Medicine (Baltimore)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Medicine (Baltimore)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">MEDI</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Medicine</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0025-7974</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1536-5964</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Wolters Kluwer Health</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6314785</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">30544467</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">MD-D-18-04035</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000013547</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="art-access-id">13547</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="hwp-journal-coll"><subject>5800</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research Article</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Meta-Analysis of Observational Studies in Epidemiology</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Association between MDM2 rs2279744, MDM2 rs937283, and p21 rs1801270 polymorphisms and retinoblastoma susceptibility</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>Qixin</given-names></name><degrees>BS</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>a</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Yun</given-names></name><degrees>BS</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>b</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>Xiaohui</given-names></name><degrees>BS</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3"><sup>c</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Weihua</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff4"><sup>d</sup></xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp"><sup>&#x02217;</sup></xref></contrib></contrib-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="editor"><name><surname>Yang.</surname><given-names>Hua</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1"><label>a</label>Department of Ophthalmology, Huzhou Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Huzhou</aff><aff id="aff2"><label>b</label>Department of Ophthalmology, Ningbo Eye Hospital, Ningbo</aff><aff id="aff3"><label>c</label>Department of Ophthalmology, Nanxun District Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Huzhou</aff><aff id="aff4"><label>d</label>Department of Ophthalmology, the First Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University, Huzhou, Zhejiang, China.</aff><author-notes id="cor1"><corresp><label>&#x02217;</label>Correspondence: Weihua Yang, Department of Ophthalmology, the First Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University, Huzhou, Zhejiang, China (e-mail: <email>yangweihuahz@163.com</email>).</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>12</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>10</day><month>12</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><volume>97</volume><issue>49</issue><elocation-id>e13547</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>10</day><month>6</month><year>2018</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>12</day><month>11</month><year>2018</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2018 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2018</copyright-year><license license-type="open-access" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0"><license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution-Non Commercial-No Derivatives License 4.0 (CCBY-NC-ND), where it is permissible to download and share the work provided it is properly cited. The work cannot be changed in any way or used commercially without permission from the journal. <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0</ext-link></license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="medi-97-e13547.pdf"/><abstract><title>Abstract</title><p>Retinoblastoma (Rb) is the most common intra-ocular malignancy in children. The association of rs2279744, and rs937283 in MDM2 gene, and p21 rs1801270 polymorphism and RB development have been demonstrated. To provide a comprehensive assessment of and to clarify associations between the 3 SNPs (MDM2 rs2279744, MDM2 rs937283, and p21 rs1801270) and the risk of RB, we performed a meta-analysis of all the eligible case-control studies. We searched English databases include PubMed, Embase, Google Scholar, and Cochrane Library, using an upper date limit of January 1, 2018. The association between MDM2 rs2279744, MDM2 rs937283, and p21 rs1801270 polymorphisms and the risk of RB were estimated by calculating a pooled OR and 95% CI under a homozygote comparison, heterozygote comparison, dominant model, and recessive model. The statistical power analysis was performed using G&#x02217;Power. Our meta-analysis showed a significant association between RB susceptibility and MDM2 rs2279744 recessive model (OR&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;1.427, 95%CI: 1.107-1.840, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.006, I<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0%). Moreover, a significant link was observed between RB risk and MDM2 rs937283 homozygote comparison (OR&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0.471, 95%CI: 0.259-0.858, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.014, I<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0%) and recessive model (OR&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0.587, 95%CI: 0.410-0.840, <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.004, I<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0%). However, no significant relationship between the p21 rs1801270 polymorphism and RB susceptibility was detected in any of the 4 models (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;&#x0003e;&#x0200a;.05). In conclusion, we found that significant association between the MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphism and increased RB risk, while MDM2 rs937283 polymorphism was associated with significantly decreased RB risk. However, as to the P21 rs1801270 polymorphism, a statistically significant association was not identified for RB.</p></abstract><kwd-group><title>Keywords</title><kwd>meta-analysis</kwd><kwd>retinoblastoma</kwd><kwd>rs1801270</kwd><kwd>rs2279744</kwd><kwd>rs937283</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>OPEN-ACCESS</meta-name><meta-value>TRUE</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec><label>1</label><title>Introduction</title><p>Retinoblastoma (Rb) is the most common intra-ocular malignancy in children and its incidence is approximately 1 case for every 15,000 to 28,000 live births.<sup>[<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]</sup> Normally, RB presents at a young age, with about two - thirds of all patients diagnosed before 2 years of age.<sup>[<xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]</sup> Clinical presentations of RB include strabismus, leukocoria, red eye, nystagmus, and loss of binocularity depending on the tumor location.<sup>[<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]</sup> The primarily treatment for RB are surgery and chemotherapy. Even if the curative effect and survival rate of children have been raised obviously, RB is still a serious threat to the health of children all over the world.<sup>[<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]</sup> RB may develop rapidly during early childhood, thus it is vital to finding tumors early and preserving vision.<sup>[<xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]</sup></p><p>Recently, researchers mainly focused on the identification of RB genetic biomarkers such as gene polymorphisms, microRNA, and lnRNA. Interestingly, some studies have shown that a series of other genes, such as cyclin-dependent kinase inhibitor 1 (p21), tumor protein p53 (p53), mouse double minute 2 homolog (MDM2), and MDM4, may influence the development of RB. p21 rs1801270 polymorphism can produce a C to A transversion and cause a substitution from serine to arginine, affecting the DNA binding zinc finger domain of the protein.<sup>[<xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]</sup> Moreover, p21 is the primary protein that is upregulated by activated p53 in response to DNA damage.<sup>[<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]</sup> MDM2 gene is an important negative regulator of the p53 suppressor gene, promoting the degradation of p53 through its E3 ubiquitin ligase activity.<sup>[<xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]</sup> The association of 2 single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) (rs2279744 and rs937283) in MDM2 gene and RB development have been demonstrated.<sup>[<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</sup></p><p>To provide a comprehensive assessment and to clarify associations between the 3 SNPs (MDM2 rs2279744, MDM2 rs937283, and p21 rs1801270) and the risk of RB, we performed a meta-analysis of all the eligible case-control studies.</p></sec><sec><label>2</label><title>Materials and methods</title><p>This systematic review and meta-analysis were conducted following the Meta-Analysis of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (MOOSE) guidelines.<sup>[<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]</sup> The secondary research was conducted in our meta-analysis by reviewing previous publications without linking to any human subjects, thus, ethical approval is not required.</p><sec><label>2.1</label><title>Literature search strategy and selection criteria</title><p>To conduct a literature search, we searched English databases include PubMed, Embase, Google Scholar, and Cochrane Library, using an upper date limit of January 1, 2018 with the following strategy: (Retinoblastoma OR Retinal Neuroblastoma OR Retinal Glioma OR Sporadic Retinoblastoma) AND (rs1801270 OR p21 Ser31Arg) OR (rs2279744 OR MDM2 SNP T309G) OR (rs937283 OR MDM2 SNP G2164A). All the included studies must meet the following criteria: studies involving the association between MDM2 rs2279744, MDM2 rs937283 and p21 rs1801270 polymorphisms and risk of RB; case-control studies based on human; studies published in English; studies with usable and sufficient original data for estimating odds ratios (OR) and their 95% confidence interval (CI). The main exclusion criteria were: duplicate articles; reviews and meta-analysis; not case-control studies; animal studies; not relevant to specific polymorphisms or RB; no sufficient and eligible raw data even after contacting the authors.</p></sec><sec><label>2.2</label><title>Literature data extraction</title><p>The following data were extracted from each included studies independently by 2 investigators: the first author's name, year of publication, country of origin, ethnicity of study population, source of control, patient number of cases and controls, and the association between the 3 SNPs (MDM2 rs2279744, MDM2 rs937283 and p21 rs1801270) and the risk of RB. The extracted data were compared, and discrepancies were solved by consensus.</p></sec><sec><label>2.3</label><title>Statistical analysis</title><p>The association between MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphism and the risk of RB was estimated by calculating a pooled OR and 95% CI under a homozygote comparison (TT vs GG), heterozygote comparison (TG vs GG), dominant model (TT+TG vs GG) and recessive model (TT vs TG+GG). To determine the link between MDM2 rs937283 polymorphism and the RB risk, homozygote comparison (AA vs GG), heterozygote comparison (AG vs GG), dominant model (AA+AG vs GG) and recessive model (AA vs AG+GG) were also operated. Similarly, homozygote comparison (CC vs AA), heterozygote comparison (CA vs AA), dominant model (CC+CA vs AA) and recessive model (CC vs CA+AA) were also conducted to explore the relationship between P21 rs1801270 polymorphism and the susceptibility to RB. The fixed-effects model or random-effects model was selected depending on whether or not heterogeneity existed among studies. The Cochrane Q test (ie, the chi-squared test) was applied to estimate heterogeneity among the included relevant studies. If <italic>I</italic><sup><italic>2</italic></sup>&#x0200a;&#x0003c;&#x0200a;50%, the fixed effects model was applied. Otherwise, the random-effects model was chosen.<sup>[<xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]</sup> Furthermore, a prediction interval was calculated under the random-effects model, because it can provide a predicted range for the true effect size.<sup>[<xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]</sup> However, studies less than 3 were not calculated prediction interval. It is worth mentioning that publication bias was only effective when there are at least 10 relevant studies exist. Otherwise, publication bias was underpowered and would have led to unreliable results.<sup>[<xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]</sup> We therefore decided to quit publication bias in this meta-analysis due to the limited included studies (only 5 trials). All meta-analyses were conducted on STATA12.0 (Stata Corporation, College Station, TX, USA). In addition, statistical power analysis was performed using G&#x02217;Power 3.1.9.2 with an &#x003b1; level of 5%.<sup>[<xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]</sup></p></sec></sec><sec><label>3</label><title>Results</title><sec><label>3.1</label><title>Included studies and the characteristics</title><p>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">1</xref> showed the process of acquiring eligible studies. 2587 records were identified from PubMed, Embase, Google Scholar, and Cochrane Library. After title and abstract evaluation, 2311 duplicates were removed and 210 were excluded for not reporting the 3 SNPs (MDM2 rs2279744, MDM2 rs937283, and p21 rs1801270) and the risk of RB. Thus, 66 unique studies left for more detailed evaluation. We found that 37 studies were not original research and 20 studies did not involve humans by reading the full text. We therefore have 9 potential studies for further analyses, however, 4 trials were removed for no usable data. Finally, 5 articles with 1526 patients were included in this meta-analysis.</p><fig id="F1" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>The process of identifying included studies.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e13547-g001"/></fig><p>According to the polymorphisms investigated, the characteristics of the included studies were summarized in Table <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">1</xref>. Four studies involved the MDM2 rs2279744,<sup>[<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup> 2 studies <sup>[<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,<xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]</sup> showed a lower risk in RB and the rest of studies <sup>[<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup> showed no significant association between MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphisms and RB risk. Two studies estimated MDM2 rs937283 <sup>[<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,<xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]</sup> with 1 trial <sup>[<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</sup> indicated a higher risk of RB and another trial <sup>[<xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]</sup> showed MDM2 rs937283 not link with RB risk. Meanwhile, 2 studies investigated p21 rs1801270 polymorphisms <sup>[<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</sup> susceptibility to RB, 1 study <sup>[<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</sup> observed higher RB susceptibility and the remaining trial <sup>[<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup> showed no significant association between RB susceptibility and p21 rs1801270 polymorphisms. Among the included studies, 2 from China,<sup>[<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup> 2 from Brazil,<sup>[<xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</sup> and 1 from Italy.<sup>[<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]</sup> Two studies investigated Han Chinese<sup>[<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup> and 1 trial involved Caucasian, Mullato or Black,<sup>[<xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]</sup> while the ethnicity of 2 studies was not available.<sup>[<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</sup> The included trials were all case-control studies, the case group all consist of RB patients, and the control group included unrelated individuals,<sup>[<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]</sup> unrelated healthy adults,<sup>[<xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</sup> healthy adults <sup>[<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup> and normal control.<sup>[<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</sup> All included studies obtained blood sample from each recruited individual for genomic DNA extraction, and were all assessed by polymerase chain reaction (PCR).</p><table-wrap id="T1" position="float"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Characteristic of Included Studies.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e13547-g002"/></table-wrap></sec><sec><label>3.2</label><title>MDM2 rs2279744, MDM2 rs937283 and p21 rs1801270 polymorphisms and susceptibility to RB</title><p>We pooled 4 studies <sup>[<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup> involving MDM2 rs2279744 to evaluate the RB risk associated with MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphisms. The meta-analysis showed a significant statistical association between RB susceptibility and MDM2 rs2279744 recessive model (TT vs TG+GG) (OR (<italic>95%CI</italic>)&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;1.427 (1.107&#x02013;1.840), <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.006, Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">2</xref>D, 95% prediction interval: 0.82&#x02013;2.50) with the fixed-effects model (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0.409, I<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0%), while no statistical significance was detected in the 3 genotypes of homozygote comparison (TT vs GG) (OR (<italic>95%CI</italic>)&#x0200a;=&#x0200a; 1.307 (0.929&#x02013;1.841), <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.125, Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">2</xref>A, 95% prediction interval: 0.40&#x02013;4.45) with the fixed-effects model (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.276, I<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;22.5%), heterozygote comparison (TG vs GG) (OR (<italic>95%CI</italic>)&#x0200a;=&#x0200a; 0.935 (0.691&#x02013;1.265), <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.664, Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">2</xref>B, 95% prediction interval: 0.48&#x02013;1.82) with the fixed-effects model (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.679, I<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0%), and dominant model (TT+TG vs GG) (OR (<italic>95%CI</italic>)&#x0200a;=&#x0200a; 1.042 (0.786&#x02013;1.382), <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.774, Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">2</xref>C, 95% prediction interval: 0.55&#x02013;1.96) with the fixed-effects model (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.388, I<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0.7%). The results indicated that the MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphisms were significantly associated with susceptibility to RB.</p><fig id="F2" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>(A) The forest plot of MDM2 rs2279744 homozygote comparison (TT vs GG) and RB risk; (B) The forest plot of MDM2 rs2279744 heterozygote comparison (TG vs GG) and RB risk; (C) The forest plot of MDM2 rs2279744dominant model (TT+TG vs GG) and RB risk; (D) The forest plot of MDM2 rs2279744recessive model (TT vs TG+GG) and RB risk. Rb = Retinoblastoma.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e13547-g003"/></fig><p>Two trials <sup>[<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,<xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]</sup> were pooled to estimate the association between RB risk and MDM2 rs937283 polymorphisms, a significant statistical association was observed between lower RB risk and MDM2 rs937283 homozygote comparison (AA vs GG) (OR (<italic>95%CI</italic>)&#x0200a;=&#x0200a; 0.471 (0.259&#x02013;0.858), <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.014, Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">3</xref>A) with the fixed-effects model (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.581, I<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0%) and recessive model (AA vs AG+GG) (OR (<italic>95%CI</italic>)&#x0200a;=&#x0200a; 0.587 (0.410&#x02013;0.840), <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.004, Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">2</xref>D) with the fixed-effects model (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.334, I<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0%). However, no significant statistical link was found in the 2 genotypes of heterozygote comparison (AG vs GG) (OR (<italic>95%CI</italic>)&#x0200a;=&#x0200a; 0.741 (0.406&#x02013;1.354), <italic>p</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0.330, Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">3</xref>B) with the fixed-effects model (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.964, I<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0%) and dominant model (AA+AG vs GG) (OR (<italic>95%CI</italic>)&#x0200a;=&#x0200a; 0.581 (0.329&#x02013;1.025), <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.061, Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">3</xref>C) with the fixed-effects model (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.708, I<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0%). The meta-analysis showed a statistical significance between lower RB risk and MDM2 rs937283 polymorphisms.</p><fig id="F3" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>(A) The forest plot of MDM2 rs937283 homozygote comparison (AA vs GG) and RB risk; (B) The forest plot of MDM2 rs937283 heterozygote comparison (AG vs GG) and RB risk; (C) The forest plot of MDM2 rs937283 dominant model (AA+AG vs GG) and RB risk; (D) The forest plot of MDM2 rs937283 recessive model (AA vs AG+GG) and RB risk. Rb = Retinoblastoma.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e13547-g004"/></fig><p>To investigate the relationship between p21 rs1801270 polymorphisms and susceptibility to RB, we combined 2 trials <sup>[<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</sup> based on homozygote comparison (CC vs AA), heterozygote comparison (CA vs AA), dominant model (CC+CA vs AA) and recessive model (CC vs CA+AA), the pooled ORs (<italic>95%CIs</italic>) were (1.242 (0.716-2.156), <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.441, Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F4">4</xref>A) with the fixed-effects model (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.437, I<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0%), (1.077 (0.651&#x02013;1.781), <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.774, Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F4">4</xref>B) with the fixed-effects model (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.699, I2&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0%), (1.115 (0.694&#x02013;1.792), <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.654, Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F4">4</xref>C) with the fixed-effects model (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.745, I<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0%) and (0.824 (0.323&#x02013;2.103), <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.685, Fig. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F4">4</xref>D) with the random-effects model (<italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;.008, I<sup>2</sup>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;85.7%), respectively. No significant statistical relationship between the p21 rs1801270 polymorphism in RB susceptibility was detected in any of the 4 models, which indicated that p21 rs1801270 polymorphism was not link with the risk of RB. All results of the analysis were shown in Table <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">2</xref>.</p><fig id="F4" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>(A) The forest plot of p21 rs1801270 homozygote comparison (CC vs AA) and RB risk; (B) The forest plot of p21 rs1801270 heterozygote comparison (CA vs AA) and RB risk; (C) The forest plot of p21 rs1801270 dominant model (CC+CA vs AA) and RB risk; (D) The forest plot of p21 rs1801270 recessive model (CC vs CA+AA) and RB risk. Rb = Retinoblastoma.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e13547-g005"/></fig><table-wrap id="T2" position="float"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Results of Analysis.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-97-e13547-g006"/></table-wrap></sec><sec><label>3.3</label><title>Power analysis</title><p>We calculated the statistical power analysis to reassess the available data when an alpha of 0.05 was assigned. As shown in Table <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">2</xref>, the statistical power ranged from 9.3% to 54.0% for MDM2 rs2279744 analysis. For MDM2 rs937283 analysis, the statistical power ranged from 14.4% to 78.2%. The power of P21 rs1801270 analysis ranged from 4.5% to 15.5%.</p></sec></sec><sec><label>4</label><title>Discussion</title><p>Early in 1809, RB was first described by the Scottish surgeon James Wardrop, as white brain-like intraocular tumors of retinal origin.<sup>[<xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</sup> With social and economic development, the understanding of the mechanism of RB is deeper day by day. Importantly, the gene plays an important role in the development of RB. Almost half of the children with RB have a hereditary genetic defect associated with RB.<sup>[<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]</sup> Although several genetic studies have reported the correlation between MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphism, MDM2 rs937283 polymorphism, or p21 rs1801270 variant and the risk of RB, these results were inconclusive since they are performed in an individual medical center with small sample size and in different ethnicities. Therefore, it is important to perform a meta-analysis of all eligible studies to clarify the effects of MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphism, MDM2 rs937283 polymorphism, or P21 rs1801270 variant on risk of RB.</p><p>To the best of our knowledge, the meta-analysis in this study is the largest to study the associations between MDM2 rs2279744, MDM2 rs937283, or P21 rs1801270 polymorphisms and RB risk. In our meta-analysis, based on the database of publications in respect of the MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphism, MDM2 rs937283 polymorphism, and the P21 rs1801270 polymorphism, among which there are 4 studies including 520 cases and 745 controls for MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphism, 2 studies including 241 cases and 254 controls for MDM2 rs937283 polymorphism, and 2 studies including 309 cases and 305 controls for P21 rs1801270 polymorphism respectively. An increased risk of RB was found for the MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphism. Likewise, we observed MDM2 rs937283 polymorphism was significantly associated with a decreased RB risk. Interestingly, as to the P21 rs1801270 polymorphism, a statistically significant association was not identified for RB.</p><p>MDM2 rs2279744 (also known as MDM2 SNP T309G) is a G/T single-nucleotide variation on human chromosome 12. It can influence the binding of the transcription factor, Sp1. Sp1 binds with higher affinity to the G allele than to the T allele, which accounts for increased transcription of the MDM2 gene and higher expression levels of MDM2 protein, and thereby inhibits the function of p53 pathway in the prevention of tumor formation.<sup>[<xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]</sup> Our results evaluated MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphism may be a risk factor for the development of RB. Prediction intervals were calculated for MDM2 rs2279744. The results of prediction intervals are wide, suggesting that future research may demonstrate benefit, disadvantage, or not demonstrate any statistically significant difference.<sup>[<xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]</sup> Similar to our analysis, some meta-analysis demonstrated that MDM2 rs2279744 is associated with squamous cell carcinoma,<sup>[<xref rid="R26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]</sup> colorectal cancer,<sup>[<xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>]</sup> endometrial cancer,<sup>[<xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]</sup> and hepatocellular carcinoma.<sup>[<xref rid="R29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]</sup> But 2 meta-analyses indicated that MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphism cannot be considered as genetic risk factors for osteosarcoma,<sup>[<xref rid="R30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>]</sup> and prostate cancer.<sup>[<xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>]</sup> More interestingly, Xie et al<sup>[<xref rid="R31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>]</sup> found MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphism has no influence on bladder cancer risk in Asians, but this single nucleotide polymorphism may be associated with genetic susceptibility of bladder cancer among Caucasians. Considering the above results, we think that MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphism may have tumor suppressor functions under certain conditions. Thus, gene-environment and gene-gene interactions regulate carcinogenesis, and the presence of some other causal factors until now unrealized evaluate an association between MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphism and RB development.</p><p>MDM2 rs937283 (also known as SNP G2164A) polymorphism could lead to an A to G base change at the 2164 nucleotide in the promoter region of MDM2 gene. Jiao et al<sup>[<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</sup> suggested that the MDM2 rs937283 polymorphism is a novel functional SNP both in vitro and in vivo as well as a biomarker for poor prognosis in RB. However, our meta-analysis proved that MDM2 rs937283 polymorphism was significantly associated with a decreased RB risk. A possible explanation is that our meta-analysis included more studies that have more patients.</p><p>The p21 rs1801270 (also named p21 Ser31Arg), which occurs in codon 31, results in an amino acid substitution of arginine for serine. This polymorphism is located in a highly conserved region of p21 and is expected to affect its molecular function.<sup>[<xref rid="R32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>]</sup> Prior study has shown an association between the p21 rs1801270A allele and a decreased risk for cervical cancer in a population of Chinese women.<sup>[<xref rid="R33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>]</sup> However, Taghavi et al <sup>[<xref rid="R34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]</sup> suggest that p21 rs1801270 is not genetic susceptibility biomarker for esophageal squamous cell carcinoma. Similarly, our analysis indicated that p21 rs1801270 is not the risk of RB development. A possible reason for this may be that the mechanism of carcinogenesis may differ between different cancer sites and the p21 rs1801270 genetic variants may exert multiple effects in different cancers.<sup>[<xref rid="R35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>]</sup></p><p>Notably, our analysis is not without limitations. First, only 5 studies were included for the meta-analysis, the case number included in our analysis is relatively small. Moreover, the statistical power for each analysis is not high. Second, gene-gene, gene-environment (including age, environmental factors, lifestyle, and some other factors) and within-gene interactions may modulate RB risk, and therefore should be identified in the future study. Finally, since the included studies were only written in English, the language bias is inevitable.</p><p>In conclusion, our meta-analysis found that significant association between the MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphism and increased RB risk. Moreover, MDM2 rs937283 polymorphism was associated with significantly decreased RB risk. Interestingly, as to the P21 rs1801270 polymorphism, a statistically significant association was not identified for RB. Considering the above-mentioned limitations, more adequately powered and well-designed studies are required to verify this conclusion.</p></sec><sec><title>Author contributions</title><p><bold>Conceptualization:</bold> Weihua Yang.</p><p><bold>Data curation:</bold> Qixin Cao, Yun Wang, and Xiaohui Song.</p><p><bold>Formal analysis:</bold> Yun Wang.</p><p><bold>Methodology:</bold> Qixin Cao and Xiaohui Song.</p><p><bold>Software:</bold> Qixin Cao and Xiaohui Song.</p><p><bold>Writing &#x02013; original draft:</bold> Qixin Cao, Yun Wang, and Weihua Yang.</p><p><bold>Writing &#x02013; review and editing:</bold> Weihua Yang.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn fn-type="abbr"><p>Abbreviations: CI = confidence interval, MDM2 = mouse double minute 2 homolog, OR = odds ratios, p21 = cyclin-dependent kinase inhibitor 1, p53 = tumor protein p53, Rb = Retinoblastoma.</p></fn><fn fn-type="equal"><p>Qixin Cao, and Yun Wang contributed equally to this work and should be considered as co-first authors.</p></fn><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="R1"><label>[1]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Parkin</surname><given-names>DM</given-names></name><name><surname>Stiller</surname><given-names>CA</given-names></name><name><surname>Draper</surname><given-names>GJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>The international incidence of childhood cancer</article-title>. <source>Int J Cancer</source>
<year>1988</year>;<volume>42</volume>:<elocation-id>511</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>20</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3170025</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>[2]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gallie</surname><given-names>BL</given-names></name><name><surname>Campbell</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Devlin</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Developmental basis of retinal-specific induction of cancer by RB mutation</article-title>. <source>Cancer Res</source>
<year>1999</year>;<volume>59</volume>:<elocation-id>1731s</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>5s</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10197588</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>[3]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Said</surname><given-names>AMA</given-names></name><name><surname>Elbayomi</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name><name><surname>Shaat</surname><given-names>AAK</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Structural changes of the macula and optic nerve head in the remaining eyes after enucleation for retinoblastoma: an optical coherence tomography study</article-title>. <source>BMC Ophthalmol</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>17</volume>:<elocation-id>251</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29246122</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>[4]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Abramson</surname><given-names>DH</given-names></name><name><surname>Beaverson</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Sangani</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Screening for retinoblastoma: presenting signs as prognosticators of patient and ocular survival</article-title>. <source>Pediatrics</source>
<year>2003</year>;<volume>112</volume>:<elocation-id>1248</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>55</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14654593</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>[5]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Benavente</surname><given-names>CA</given-names></name><name><surname>Dyer</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Genetics and epigenetics of human retinoblastoma</article-title>. <source>Annu Rev Pathol</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>10</volume>:<elocation-id>547</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>62</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25621664</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>[6]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Skalet</surname><given-names>AH</given-names></name><name><surname>Gombos</surname><given-names>DS</given-names></name><name><surname>Gallie</surname><given-names>BL</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Screening children at risk for retinoblastoma: consensus report from the American Association of Ophthalmic Oncologists and Pathologists</article-title>. <source>Ophthalmology</source>
<year>2018</year>;<volume>125</volume>:<elocation-id>453</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>8</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29056300</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>[7]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Hildesheim</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>No point mutation but a codon 31ser--&#x0003e;arg polymorphism of the WAF-1/CIP-1/p21 tumor suppressor gene in nasopharyngeal carcinoma (NPC): the polymorphism distinguishes Caucasians from Chinese</article-title>. <source>Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev</source>
<year>1995</year>;<volume>4</volume>:<elocation-id>261</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>7</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7606201</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>[8]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gartel</surname><given-names>AL</given-names></name><name><surname>Radhakrishnan</surname><given-names>SK</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Lost in transcription: p21 repression, mechanisms, and consequences</article-title>. <source>Cancer Res</source>
<year>2005</year>;<volume>65</volume>:<elocation-id>3980</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>5</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15899785</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>[9]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bond</surname><given-names>GL</given-names></name><name><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name><surname>Bond</surname><given-names>EE</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>A single nucleotide polymorphism in the MDM2 promoter attenuates the p53 tumor suppressor pathway and accelerates tumor formation in humans</article-title>. <source>Cell</source>
<year>2004</year>;<volume>119</volume>:<elocation-id>591</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>602</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15550242</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R10"><label>[10]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jiao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>A functional polymorphism (rs937283) in the MDM2 promoter region is associated with poor prognosis of retinoblastoma in Chinese Han population</article-title>. <source>Sci Rep</source>
<year>2016</year>;<volume>6</volume>:<elocation-id>31240</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27506496</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R11"><label>[11]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Stroup</surname><given-names>DF</given-names></name><name><surname>Berlin</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><name><surname>Morton</surname><given-names>SC</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Meta-analysis of observational studies in epidemiology: a proposal for reporting. Meta-analysis Of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (MOOSE) group</article-title>. <source>Jama</source>
<year>2000</year>;<volume>283</volume>:<elocation-id>2008</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>12</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10789670</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R12"><label>[12]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lan</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Efficacy of fibrin glue versus sutures for attaching conjunctival autografts in pterygium surgery: a systematic review with meta-analysis and trial sequential analysis of evidence</article-title>. <source>Oncotarget</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>8</volume>:<elocation-id>41487</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>97</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28489563</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R13"><label>[13]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>TC</given-names></name><name><surname>Spiegelhalter</surname><given-names>DJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Bayesian approaches to random-effects meta-analysis: a comparative study</article-title>. <source>Stat Med</source>
<year>1995</year>;<volume>14</volume>:<elocation-id>2685</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>99</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8619108</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R14"><label>[14]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>SG</given-names></name><name><surname>Spiegelhalter</surname><given-names>DJ</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>A re-evaluation of random-effects meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>J Roy Stat Soc Ser A (Stat Soc)</source>
<year>2009</year>;<volume>172</volume>:<elocation-id>137</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>59</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R15"><label>[15]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Bradburn</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Deeks</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Metan: fixed-and random-effects meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>Stata J</source>
<year>2008</year>;<volume>8</volume>:<elocation-id>3</elocation-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R16"><label>[16]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sterne</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><name><surname>Gavaghan</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Egger</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Publication and related bias in meta-analysis: power of statistical tests and prevalence in the literature</article-title>. <source>J Clin Epidemiol</source>
<year>2000</year>;<volume>53</volume>:<elocation-id>1119</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>29</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11106885</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R17"><label>[17]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Faul</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Erdfelder</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Buchner</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Statistical power analyses using G&#x02217;Power 3.1: tests for correlation and regression analyses</article-title>. <source>Behav Res Methods</source>
<year>2009</year>;<volume>41</volume>:<elocation-id>1149</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>60</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19897823</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R18"><label>[18]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Epistolato</surname><given-names>MC</given-names></name><name><surname>Disciglio</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name><surname>Livide</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>p53 Arg72Pro and MDM2 309 SNPs in hereditary retinoblastoma</article-title>. <source>J Hum Genet</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>56</volume>:<elocation-id>685</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>6</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21814224</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R19"><label>[19]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>de Oliveira Reis</surname><given-names>AH</given-names></name><name><surname>de Carvalho</surname><given-names>IN</given-names></name><name><surname>de Sousa Damasceno</surname><given-names>PB</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Influence of MDM2 and MDM4 on development and survival in hereditary retinoblastoma</article-title>. <source>Pediatr Blood Cancer</source>
<year>2012</year>;<volume>59</volume>:<elocation-id>39</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>43</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22180099</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R20"><label>[20]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Ye</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Association of p53 rs1042522, MDM2 rs2279744, and p21 rs1801270 polymorphisms with retinoblastoma risk and invasion in a Chinese population</article-title>. <source>Sci Rep</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>5</volume>:<elocation-id>13300</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26289323</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R21"><label>[21]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Carvalho</surname><given-names>IN</given-names></name><name><surname>Reis</surname><given-names>AH</given-names></name><name><surname>Cabello</surname><given-names>PH</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Polymorphisms of CDKN1A gene and risk of retinoblastoma</article-title>. <source>Carcinogenesis</source>
<year>2013</year>;<volume>34</volume>:<elocation-id>2774</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>7</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24045412</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R22"><label>[22]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kivela</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>200 years of success initiated by James Wardrop's 1809 monograph on retinoblastoma</article-title>. <source>Acta Ophthalmol</source>
<year>2009</year>;<volume>87</volume>:<elocation-id>810</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>2</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20002017</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R23"><label>[23]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>MacCarthy</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Birch</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name><name><surname>Draper</surname><given-names>GJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Retinoblastoma in Great Britain 1963&#x02013;2002</article-title>. <source>Br J Ophthalmol</source>
<year>2009</year>;<volume>93</volume>:<elocation-id>33</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>7</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18838413</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R24"><label>[24]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tas</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Atabey</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Caglayan</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Investigation of the association between the MDM2 T309G polymorphism and gastric cancer</article-title>. <source>Biomed Rep</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>7</volume>:<elocation-id>469</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>73</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29181159</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R25"><label>[25]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Riley</surname><given-names>RD</given-names></name><name><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name><surname>Deeks</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Interpretation of random effects meta-analyses</article-title>. <source>Bmj</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>342</volume>:<elocation-id>d549</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21310794</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R26"><label>[26]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Influence of MDM2 polymorphisms on squamous cell carcinoma susceptibility: a meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>Onco Targets Ther</source>
<year>2016</year>;<volume>9</volume>:<elocation-id>6211</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>24</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27785069</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R27"><label>[27]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name><surname>Du</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Gu</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>MDM2 SNP309 polymorphism is associated with colorectal cancer risk</article-title>. <source>Sci Rep</source>
<year>2014</year>;<volume>4</volume>:<elocation-id>4851</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24797837</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R28"><label>[28]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>LH</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>WT</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>MDM2 rs2279744 polymorphism and endometrial cancer: a meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>Tumour Biol</source>
<year>2014</year>;<volume>35</volume>:<elocation-id>3167</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>70</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24293392</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R29"><label>[29]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Bian</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>MDM2 SNP309 rs2279744 polymorphism and gastric cancer risk: a meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>PLoS One</source>
<year>2013</year>;<volume>8</volume>:<elocation-id>e56918</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23451111</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R30"><label>[30]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bilbao-Aldaiturriaga</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Askaiturrieta</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Granado-Tajada</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>A systematic review and meta-analysis of MDM2 polymorphisms in osteosarcoma susceptibility</article-title>. <source>Pediatr Res</source>
<year>2016</year>;<volume>80</volume>:<elocation-id>472</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>9</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27438225</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R31"><label>[31]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Association between MDM2 SNP309 T&#x0003e;G polymorphism and the risk of bladder cancer: new data in a Chinese population and an updated meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>Onco Targets Ther</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>8</volume>:<elocation-id>3679</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>90</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26672516</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R32"><label>[32]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chedid</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Michieli</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Lengel</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>A single nucleotide substitution at codon 31&#x0200a;(Ser/Arg) defines a polymorphism in a highly conserved region of the p53-inducible gene WAF1/CIP1</article-title>. <source>Oncogene</source>
<year>1994</year>;<volume>9</volume>:<elocation-id>3021</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>4</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8084608</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R33"><label>[33]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Association of p21 SNPs and risk of cervical cancer among Chinese women</article-title>. <source>BMC Cancer</source>
<year>2012</year>;<volume>12</volume>:<elocation-id>589</elocation-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23231583</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R34"><label>[34]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Taghavi</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Biramijamal</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Abbaszadegan</surname><given-names>MR</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>P21(waf1/cip1) gene polymorphisms and possible interaction with cigarette smoking in esophageal squamous cell carcinoma in northeastern Iran: a preliminary study</article-title>. <source>Arch Iran Med</source>
<year>2010</year>;<volume>13</volume>:<elocation-id>235</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>42</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20433229</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R35"><label>[35]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Pu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Association between the ERCC2 Asp312Asn polymorphism and risk of cancer</article-title>. <source>Oncotarget</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>8</volume>:<elocation-id>48488</elocation-id>&#x02013;<lpage>506</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28489582</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>